<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Rulebook name="SR4A">
<!-- Start Qualities -->
	<Quality name="Ambidextrous" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			The character can use and handle objects equally well with both hands. The character does not suffer any modifiers for using an off-hand weapon (see p 150). When using two weapons at once, however, the character must still split his dice pool.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Animal Empathy" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with Animal Empathy has an instinctive feel for handling animals of all kinds. The character receives a +2 dice pool modifier for all tests involving the influence or control of an animal (including riding). Characters with this quality become more sensitive to the animal's point of view, and are typically reluctant to harm or show cruelty to an animal. This quality does not affect a character's interaction with sentient critters, such as sasquatches, naga, or dragons.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Aptitude" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Aptitude quality is a prodigy in one particular skill. Characters with this quality may improve one Active skill one point above its natural maximum to a 7. Note that this doesn't actually increase a skill that's currently at Rating 6; it just opens the door for further advancement. Increasing a skill level beyond 6 costs double the normal Karma Cost (see Character Improvement, p. 269). The Aptitude quality may be taken during character creation to allow a beginning character to start with a skill of 7. If a character takes advantage of this quality, the cost for raising the skill from 6 to 7 is also twice normal, or 8 BP. Characters may only take the Aptitude quality once.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
		<Quality name="Astral Chameleon" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			With the Astral Chameleon quality, the character's astral signature blends into the background of astral space more quickly. All signatures left by the character last only half as long, and others assensing the signature receive a -2 dice pool modifier. Only characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities may take this quality.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
		<Quality name="Blandness" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			This character blends into any crowd. He is average in height, weight, and appearance, and has a distinct lack of distinguishing physical characteristics or mannerisms. Anyone attempting to describe the character cannot come up with anything more precise than "he was kinda average." Individuals attempting to shadow or physically locate the character through social means or in even slightly crowded settings receive a -2 dice pool modifier on all tests made during such attempts.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
		<Quality name="Codeslinger" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A codeslinger is particularly adept at performing a particular Matrix action and receives a +2 dice pool modifier to that Matrix action. Only Matrix actions with an associated success test apply; Codeslinger does not apply to actions that do not require a success test, such as Jack Out. Codeslinger may only be taken once.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
		<Quality name="Double Jointed" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A Double Jointed character has unusually flexible joints and can bend and contort his body into extreme positions. The character receives a +2 dice pool modifier for Escape Artist Tests (p. 133). At the gamemaster's discretion, the character may be able to squeeze into small, cramped spaces where less limber characters couldn't fit.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
		<Quality name="Erased A" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Better than SINless-the character with this quality officially doesn't exist and never did; someone or something actively works to remove her traces from the system. Maybe it's an elite hacker who owes her a favor or an AI she befriended, but the end result is that her data trail and records vanish from all but the most secure systems shortly after being entered. For 5 BP, criminal SINs and unwanted data disappear within a week. For 10 BP, any SIN, undesirable credit history, or personal information on the Matrix that she wishes is burnt after 24 hours. Obviously, the eraser will preserve any data the character wishes preserved and that is vital for her to function in society. Note that vanishing data may prove an unwanted complication if the character is in custody or doing prison time (the Man may "forget" she is there).
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Erased B" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			*Choose Erased 1 or 2 but not both* Better than SINless-the character with this quality officially doesn't exist and never did; someone or something actively works to remove her traces from the system. Maybe it's an elite hacker who owes her a favor or an AI she befriended, but the end result is that her data trail and records vanish from all but the most secure systems shortly after being entered. For 5 BP, criminal SINs and unwanted data disappear within a week. For 10 BP, any SIN, undesirable credit history, or personal information on the Matrix that she wishes is burnt after 24 hours. Obviously, the eraser will preserve any data the character wishes preserved and that is vital for her to function in society. Note that vanishing data may prove an unwanted complication if the character is in custody or doing prison time (the Man may "forget" she is there).
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Exceptional Attribute" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			The Exceptional Attribute quality allows a character to possess a natural Physical or Mental attribute at a level above the metatype maximum. A character with this quality has one attribute with a natural maximum one point higher than his metatype would normally allow (for example, a human character would have one attribute with a natural maximum of 7). This also increases the augmented maximum for that attribute as appropriate. This quality may only be taken once.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="First Impression" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the First Impression quality slides easily into new situations, groups, cities, and jobs. Whenever attempting to fit into a new environment-such as infiltrating a group or trying to meet contacts in a new city-the character gains a +2 dice pool modifier on any Social Tests during the first meeting. This modifier does not apply to second and subsequent encounters.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Focused Concentration 1" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A magician character with Focused Concentration has a naturally strong ability to concentrate. This allows him to channel mana more efficiently, making him less susceptible to Drain. A character with this quality gains a +1 dice pool modifier per rating point for all Drain Tests. Only characters with the Magician or Mystic Adept qualities may take Focused Concentration.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Focused Concentration 2" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A magician character with Focused Concentration has a naturally strong ability to concentrate. This allows him to channel mana more efficiently, making him less susceptible to Drain. A character with this quality gains a +1 dice pool modifier per rating point for all Drain Tests. Only characters with the Magician or Mystic Adept qualities may take Focused Concentration.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Guts" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with Guts is not easily frightened. He receives a +2 dice pool modifier on tests made to resist fear and intimidation, including magically induced fear from spells or critter powers.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="High Pain Tolerance 1" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with Guts is not easily frightened. He receives a +2 dice pool modifier on tests made to resist fear and intimidation, including magically induced fear from spells or critter powers.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="High Pain Tolerance 2" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with Guts is not easily frightened. He receives a +2 dice pool modifier on tests made to resist fear and intimidation, including magically induced fear from spells or critter powers.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="High Pain Tolerance 3" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with Guts is not easily frightened. He receives a +2 dice pool modifier on tests made to resist fear and intimidation, including magically induced fear from spells or critter powers.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Home Ground" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Home Ground provides a character with a +2 dice pool modifier for all Active Skill Tests made within the character's home turf. Any Knowledge skills relevant to the people, places, or things within this area receive a +4 dice pool modifier. The character's home turf is a particular location with which the character is intimately familiar. The location must either be a small area-no larger than a large building or small neighborhood-or an environment encountered infrequently during the campaign. For example, in a Seattle-based campaign, the desert would be an infrequently encountered region and could be considered home ground. The desert would not be a suitable home ground for a campaign set in the magic-soaked Mojave. Gamemasters must approve all home grounds in their campaigns. For hackers and technomancers, a home ground might be a particular computer network the character knows extremely well. In this case, the character receives a +2 dice pool modifier for all tests made while accessing that network. Favorite data havens like the Denver Nexus make suitable home grounds for hacker characters. Many corporate hackers have the Home Ground quality for their corporate systems. All home grounds must be fixed locations-characters cannot move them around. If a character's home ground is destroyed, the quality is lost.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Human-Looking" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A metahuman character with the Human-Looking quality can "pass" for human in most circumstances. Human NPCs respond with neutral attitudes toward such characters when making Social Skill Tests (see p. 130). The character may suffer increased animosity from metahuman NPCs who are prejudiced against humans and who mistake him for human (or think that he is trying too hard to "look human"). Only elves, dwarfs, and orks can take the Human-Looking quality.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Lucky" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			This quality allows a character to possess an Edge attribute one point higher than his metatype maximum. (For example, a human character could raise his Edge to 8.) Note that this does not actually increase the character's Edge, it just allows him to do so; the Karma cost for improvement must still be paid (see Character Improvement, p. 269). This quality may only be taken once.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Magician" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			A character with this quality is a magician and starts with a Magic attribute of 1. This may be increased like any other attribute, up to a maximum of 6 + initiation grade (see Purchase Attributes, p. 82). A character with this quality cannot take the Adept, Mystic Adept, or Technomancer qualities. Magicians can cast spells and conjure spirits (see p. 176). The Combat Mage, Occult Investigator, Radical Eco-Shaman, and Street Shaman sample characters on pp. 99, 106, 107, and 111 are examples of magicians. Each magician follows a specific magical tradition that defines his worldview and how he perceives and manipulates magic. Two common traditions-hermetic and shamanic-are described in this book, but players can also devise their own (see Traditions, p. 180). Magicians may also have a mentor spirit (see Mentor Spirits, p. 200) that confers its own benefits or penalties; players should note these, especially when choosing spells. Magicians also have astral perception and the ability to astrally project (see The Astral World, p. 191). Though this quality is inexpensive, gamemasters should be careful not to allow it to be abused. It should only be taken for characters that are intended to be played as magicians.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Magic Resistance 1" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			For every 5 BP spent on Magic Resistance, a character receives 1 additional die for Spell Resistance Tests (see p. 183). The Magical Resistance quality, however, works even against beneficial spells such as Heal. Characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities cannot take this quality. A magically resistant character cannot choose to lower his magical resistance; it affects all spells and magical effects, good or bad. A character with Magic Resistance is never a willing subject for spells that require a voluntary subject; such spells automatically fail when used on magic resistant characters.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Magic Resistance 2" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			For every 5 BP spent on Magic Resistance, a character receives 1 additional die for Spell Resistance Tests (see p. 183). The Magical Resistance quality, however, works even against beneficial spells such as Heal. Characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities cannot take this quality. A magically resistant character cannot choose to lower his magical resistance; it affects all spells and magical effects, good or bad. A character with Magic Resistance is never a willing subject for spells that require a voluntary subject; such spells automatically fail when used on magic resistant characters.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Magic Resistance 3" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			For every 5 BP spent on Magic Resistance, a character receives 1 additional die for Spell Resistance Tests (see p. 183). The Magical Resistance quality, however, works even against beneficial spells such as Heal. Characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities cannot take this quality. A magically resistant character cannot choose to lower his magical resistance; it affects all spells and magical effects, good or bad. A character with Magic Resistance is never a willing subject for spells that require a voluntary subject; such spells automatically fail when used on magic resistant characters.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Magic Resistance 4" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			For every 5 BP spent on Magic Resistance, a character receives 1 additional die for Spell Resistance Tests (see p. 183). The Magical Resistance quality, however, works even against beneficial spells such as Heal. Characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities cannot take this quality. A magically resistant character cannot choose to lower his magical resistance; it affects all spells and magical effects, good or bad. A character with Magic Resistance is never a willing subject for spells that require a voluntary subject; such spells automatically fail when used on magic resistant characters.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Mentor Spirit" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			This quality is only available to characters with either the Magician, Adept, or Mystic Adept quality. The character has a patron mentor spirit (see Mentor Spirits, p. 200) that guides him in his practice of magic and provides certain advantages and disadvantages. A character may only ever have one mentor spirit.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Murky Link" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Any ritual sorcery (p. 184) directed against the character receives a -3 dice pool modifier. Note that this quality may work against the character in some circumstances, such as when friendly magicians want to use ritual sorcery to locate or aid the character.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Mystic Adept" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Mystic adepts are a hybrid between magicians and adepts. Mystic adepts choose whether to dedicate their individual Magic attribute points toward somatic adept powers (gaining 1 Power point per Magic attribute point allocated) or towards Magic skills such as spellcasting and conjuring instead. A character must purchase this quality in order to be a mystic adept and starts with a Magic attribute of 1. This may be increased like any other attribute, up to a maximum of 6 + initiation grade (see Purchase Attributes, p. 82). A character with this quality cannot take the Adept, Magician, or Technomancer qualities. Like adepts, mystic adepts do not have access to astral space unless they purchase the Astral Perception adept power. Mystic adepts may not astrally project. Though this quality is inexpensive, gamemasters should be careful not to allow it to be abused. It should only be taken for characters that intend to explore their nature as mystic adepts.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Natural Immunity A" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Characters with Natural Immunity have an innate or developed immunity to one single disease or toxin. This quality is available at two levels. If purchased at the 5 BP level, the character is immune to a single natural disease or toxin. If Natural Immunity is purchased at the full 15 BP level, the character is immune to a single synthetic (artificially created) disease or toxin. Natural Immunity does not affect diseases or toxins which are magically based, such as HMHVV. The player and gamemaster must agree on the disease, drug, or poison to which the character is immune. It must be something the character would have a reasonable chance of coming into contact with. The character can take one dose of the agent every (12 - Body) hours with no ill effects. If the character ingests more than a single dose during that period, he takes damage as normal, but recovery time is halved. Note that characters with Natural Immunity to a disease may still infect other characters with the disease, even though they are not suffering any ill effects from it.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Natural Immunity B" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			Characters with Natural Immunity have an innate or developed immunity to one single disease or toxin. This quality is available at two levels. If purchased at the 5 BP level, the character is immune to a single natural disease or toxin. If Natural Immunity is purchased at the full 15 BP level, the character is immune to a single synthetic (artificially created) disease or toxin. Natural Immunity does not affect diseases or toxins which are magically based, such as HMHVV. The player and gamemaster must agree on the disease, drug, or poison to which the character is immune. It must be something the character would have a reasonable chance of coming into contact with. The character can take one dose of the agent every (12 - Body) hours with no ill effects. If the character ingests more than a single dose during that period, he takes damage as normal, but recovery time is halved. Note that characters with Natural Immunity to a disease may still infect other characters with the disease, even though they are not suffering any ill effects from it.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Photographic Memory" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with Photographic Memory rarely forgets anything he has experienced. The character can instantly recall faces, dates, numbers, or anything else he has seen or heard. When making Memory Tests (see Attribute-Only Tests, p. 61), the character gains a -1 threshold modifier to the test.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Quick Healer" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A Quick Healer recovers from damage more quickly than other characters. The character receives a +2 dice pool modifier to all Healing Tests made on/for/by him, including magical healing.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Resistance to Pathogens/Toxins A" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with Resistance to Pathogens/Toxins can fight off toxins and drugs more easily than other characters and receives a +1 dice pool modifier to Resistance Tests. This quality comes at two levels; at 5 BP the character is resistant to either pathogens or toxins, not both. If the character purchases this quality at 10 BP, he is resistant to both.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Resistance to Pathogens/Toxins B" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			A character with Resistance to Pathogens/Toxins can fight off toxins and drugs more easily than other characters and receives a +1 dice pool modifier to Resistance Tests. This quality comes at two levels; at 5 BP the character is resistant to either pathogens or toxins, not both. If the character purchases this quality at 10 BP, he is resistant to both.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Spirit Affinity" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Characters with Spirit Affnity are naturally attuned to one type of spirit (see Spirits, p. 302). These spirits find the character interesting, will be drawn to him, and are more inclined to assist the character. In certain situations, they may be reluctant to attack the character, using a nonlethal power if forced to attack regardless. This quality may be taken by any character, not just magicians; magicians may possess this quality for a type of spirit that is not part of their magical tradition.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Technomancer" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Technomancers can access and manipulate the Matrix through their own sheer force of will (see Technomancers, p. 239). Known as otaku prior to the Crash of 2064, technomancers have emerged among all walks of life since the advent of augmented reality. A character must purchase this quality in order to be a technomancer and will start with a Resonance attribute of 1. This may be increased like any other attribute, up to a maximum of 6 (see Purchase Attributes, p. 83). A character with this quality cannot take the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities. Technomancers have a living persona-their Matrix alter ego- with its own separate set of attributes that govern virtual actions in the Matrix. The Resonance attribute, combined with certain other attributes, determines how strong (or weak) the persona is.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Toughness" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Characters with the Toughness quality shrug off damage more easily than others. Such characters gain a +1 dice pool modifier to their Body when making Damage Resistance Tests.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<Quality name="Will to Live" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			For each rating point in Will to Live, the character gains 1 additional Damage Overflow Box (see p. 163). These additional boxes only allow the character to sustain additional damage before dying; they do not raise the threshold at which the character becomes unconscious or incapacitated. They also don't affect wound modifiers from damage the character has taken.
		</Desc>
	</Quality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Mild Addiction 1" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is omnipresent but not blatant or intrusive; it may not even be recognized or acknowledged. At this stage it is easier to seek help, but very few recognize their addiction as something needing help at this stage. Addicts experience cravings at least once a week (if not every few days), but can ignore them if necessary without too much difficulty. The addict suffers a -2 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to resist the craving.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Mild Addiction 2" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is omnipresent but not blatant or intrusive; it may not even be recognized or acknowledged. At this stage it is easier to seek help, but very few recognize their addiction as something needing help at this stage. Addicts experience cravings at least once a week (if not every few days), but can ignore them if necessary without too much difficulty. The addict suffers a -2 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to resist the craving.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Mild Addiction 3" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is omnipresent but not blatant or intrusive; it may not even be recognized or acknowledged. At this stage it is easier to seek help, but very few recognize their addiction as something needing help at this stage. Addicts experience cravings at least once a week (if not every few days), but can ignore them if necessary without too much difficulty. The addict suffers a -2 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to resist the craving.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Moderate Addiction 1" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction at this stage is marked and difficult to overcome. Addicts experience cravings at least once a day (if not more), and they are more difficult to ignore. The addict suffers a -4 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to resist the craving.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Moderate Addiction 2" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction at this stage is marked and difficult to overcome. Addicts experience cravings at least once a day (if not more), and they are more difficult to ignore. The addict suffers a -4 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to resist the craving.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Severe Addiction 1" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is out of control. The addict experiences constant cravings (at least twice a day), suffering a -6 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to keep from giving in.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Severe Addiction 2" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is out of control. The addict experiences constant cravings (at least twice a day), suffering a -6 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to keep from giving in.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Burnout Addiction" cost="30">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. This is the same as a Severe addiction, except the addict has been in this state for some time and is experiencing the tell-tale signs of habitual use on his body. Reduce the character's Essence by 1 to reflect a loss of health from abusing his body. If the character does not kick the habit soon, he will continue to lose Essence at a rate determined by the gamemaster until he dies.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Mild Allergy" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Allergy quality is allergic to a substance or condition. The value of this quality depends on two factors. First, determine whether the substance or condition is Uncommon (2 BP) or Common (7 BP). Then determine the severity of the symptoms: Mild (3 BP), Moderate (8 BP), or Severe (13 BP). Add the appropriate point values to find the final value. For example, the value of an Uncommon Moderate Allergy is 10 (2 + 8) points.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Moderate Allergy" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Allergy quality is allergic to a substance or condition. The value of this quality depends on two factors. First, determine whether the substance or condition is Uncommon (2 BP) or Common (7 BP). Then determine the severity of the symptoms: Mild (3 BP), Moderate (8 BP), or Severe (13 BP). Add the appropriate point values to find the final value. For example, the value of an Uncommon Moderate Allergy is 10 (2 + 8) points.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Severe Allergy" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Allergy quality is allergic to a substance or condition. The value of this quality depends on two factors. First, determine whether the substance or condition is Uncommon (2 BP) or Common (7 BP). Then determine the severity of the symptoms: Mild (3 BP), Moderate (8 BP), or Severe (13 BP). Add the appropriate point values to find the final value. For example, the value of an Uncommon Moderate Allergy is 10 (2 + 8) points.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Deadly Allergy" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Allergy quality is allergic to a substance or condition. The value of this quality depends on two factors. First, determine whether the substance or condition is Uncommon (2 BP) or Common (7 BP). Then determine the severity of the symptoms: Mild (3 BP), Moderate (8 BP), or Severe (13 BP). Add the appropriate point values to find the final value. For example, the value of an Uncommon Moderate Allergy is 10 (2 + 8) points.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Astral Beacon" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Addiction quality is addicted to alcohol, drugs, BTL chips, or a similar substance with a detrimental effect on the character's health (note that nicotine, caffeine, and sugar do not count). Thee value of this quality depends on how severe the addiction is: Mild, Moderate, Severe, or Burnout. The addiction is out of control. The addict experiences constant cravings (at least twice a day), suffering a -6 dice pool modifier to Willpower and/or Body Tests to keep from giving in.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
		<NegativeQuality name="Bad Luck" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			This character is cursed-his own luck often turns against him. Whenever this character uses Edge, roll 1D6. On a result of 1, the Edge is spent, but it has the exact opposite effect intended. For example, if a character hopes to gain additional dice, instead he loses that many dice from his dice pool. If a character spends Edge to go first in an Initiative Pass, he ends up going last. If a character spent Edge to negate a glitch, Bad Luck turns it into a critical glitch.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
		<NegativeQuality name="Codeblock" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Codeblock quality always has trouble with a particular Matrix action. He receives a -2 dice pool modifier any time he attempts that type of Matrix action. Codeblock only applies to Matrix actions with an associated test; it does not apply to actions that do not require a test (jacking out, for example). Gamemasters should not allow non-hackers to apply Codeblock towards hacking actions that they are never likely to take.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Combat Paralysis" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			A character with Combat Paralysis freezes in combat situations. On the character's first Initiative Test in combat, the character only rolls half his Initiative attribute. On the second and subsequent Initiative Tests, however, the character rolls his normal Initiative. The character also receives a -3 dice pool modifier on Surprise Tests. Finally, the gamemaster should apply a +1 threshold modifier to any composure tests (see Composure, p. 138) the character must make in combat situations.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Elf Poser" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Elf Posers are human characters who want to be elves. This desire prompts them to associate with elves as much as possible, talk like elves, and alter their appearances so that they resemble elves. Real elves consider them an embarrassment, many humans think of them as sellouts, and even the other metatypes generally consider posers to be pathetic. Characters with this quality who have undergone cosmetic surgery to get "elf ears" and "elf eyes" may successfully pass as elves and avoid any negative Social skill modifiers associated with being a nonelf. If an elf discovers the character's secret, however, the elf is likely to treat him with contempt and hostility (see the Social Modifiers Table, p. 131). An outed elf poser may also face stigma from other humans as "race traitors," if those humans harbor any prejudice against elves. Only human characters may take the Elf Poser quality.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Gremlins 1" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Characters with the Gremlins quality never seem to get along with technology. Devices malfunction inexplicably in the character's hands, software constantly crashes whenever he uses it, components become unusually fragile at his touch, and wireless links suffer faltering connections and odd interference. For every 5 BP gained in this quality, reduce the number of rolled 1s necessary to get a glitch (p. 62) by 1 whenever the character is attempting to use a moderately sophisticated device (late 20th century technology or later). For example, a character with a dice pool of 8 and Gremlins Rating 2 (10 BP) would trigger a glitch if two or more 1s result from the test. The gamemaster may also require the character to make a test for operations that would otherwise succeed automatically, simply to see whether or not a glitch occurs. This effect only applies to external equipment and does not affect cyberware, bioware, or other implants.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Gremlins 2" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Characters with the Gremlins quality never seem to get along with technology. Devices malfunction inexplicably in the character's hands, software constantly crashes whenever he uses it, components become unusually fragile at his touch, and wireless links suffer faltering connections and odd interference. For every 5 BP gained in this quality, reduce the number of rolled 1s necessary to get a glitch (p. 62) by 1 whenever the character is attempting to use a moderately sophisticated device (late 20th century technology or later). For example, a character with a dice pool of 8 and Gremlins Rating 2 (10 BP) would trigger a glitch if two or more 1s result from the test. The gamemaster may also require the character to make a test for operations that would otherwise succeed automatically, simply to see whether or not a glitch occurs. This effect only applies to external equipment and does not affect cyberware, bioware, or other implants.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Gremlins 3" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Characters with the Gremlins quality never seem to get along with technology. Devices malfunction inexplicably in the character's hands, software constantly crashes whenever he uses it, components become unusually fragile at his touch, and wireless links suffer faltering connections and odd interference. For every 5 BP gained in this quality, reduce the number of rolled 1s necessary to get a glitch (p. 62) by 1 whenever the character is attempting to use a moderately sophisticated device (late 20th century technology or later). For example, a character with a dice pool of 8 and Gremlins Rating 2 (10 BP) would trigger a glitch if two or more 1s result from the test. The gamemaster may also require the character to make a test for operations that would otherwise succeed automatically, simply to see whether or not a glitch occurs. This effect only applies to external equipment and does not affect cyberware, bioware, or other implants.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Gremlins 4" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Characters with the Gremlins quality never seem to get along with technology. Devices malfunction inexplicably in the character's hands, software constantly crashes whenever he uses it, components become unusually fragile at his touch, and wireless links suffer faltering connections and odd interference. For every 5 BP gained in this quality, reduce the number of rolled 1s necessary to get a glitch (p. 62) by 1 whenever the character is attempting to use a moderately sophisticated device (late 20th century technology or later). For example, a character with a dice pool of 8 and Gremlins Rating 2 (10 BP) would trigger a glitch if two or more 1s result from the test. The gamemaster may also require the character to make a test for operations that would otherwise succeed automatically, simply to see whether or not a glitch occurs. This effect only applies to external equipment and does not affect cyberware, bioware, or other implants.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Incompetent 1" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character who is Incompetent possesses a total lack of knowledge or ability with a certain Active skill. If this quality is taken, the player must specify an Active skill in which the character is Incompetent. Incompetent may not be applied to Language or Knowledge skills. The character is treated as having a skill level of "unaware" for that particular skill (see the Skill Ratings Table, beginning on p. 119 for more information). In some cases, a Success Test may be required to perform certain tasks that most people take for granted. Characters may not possess that skill, nor may they default on it. Gamemasters are free to reject any choices that would prove irrelevant or exploitative in actual play (ie. such as Incompetent: Pilot Aerospace in a campaign where characters are street-level gangers). incompetent may be purchased more than once, choosing a separate skill each time.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Incompetent 2" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character who is Incompetent possesses a total lack of knowledge or ability with a certain Active skill. If this quality is taken, the player must specify an Active skill in which the character is Incompetent. Incompetent may not be applied to Language or Knowledge skills. The character is treated as having a skill level of "unaware" for that particular skill (see the Skill Ratings Table, beginning on p. 119 for more information). In some cases, a Success Test may be required to perform certain tasks that most people take for granted. Characters may not possess that skill, nor may they default on it. Gamemasters are free to reject any choices that would prove irrelevant or exploitative in actual play (ie. such as Incompetent: Pilot Aerospace in a campaign where characters are street-level gangers). incompetent may be purchased more than once, choosing a separate skill each time.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Incompetent 3" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character who is Incompetent possesses a total lack of knowledge or ability with a certain Active skill. If this quality is taken, the player must specify an Active skill in which the character is Incompetent. Incompetent may not be applied to Language or Knowledge skills. The character is treated as having a skill level of "unaware" for that particular skill (see the Skill Ratings Table, beginning on p. 119 for more information). In some cases, a Success Test may be required to perform certain tasks that most people take for granted. Characters may not possess that skill, nor may they default on it. Gamemasters are free to reject any choices that would prove irrelevant or exploitative in actual play (ie. such as Incompetent: Pilot Aerospace in a campaign where characters are street-level gangers). incompetent may be purchased more than once, choosing a separate skill each time.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Infirm" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			The Infirm quality represents a character with substandard physical fitness. Infirm characters could be old or simply quite ill, or they may be individuals in poor health who neglect their physical well-being, such as "couch potato" hackers or magicians. The cost for learning or improving Physical skills is twice normal (including at character creation) for Infirm characters, and they may never learn any Physical skill groups. Additionally, Infirm characters are treated as "unaware" in any Physical skills that they do not possess at Rating 1 or higher (see Skill Ratings, p. 118), and they may not default on skill tests for that skill. The quality does not affect performance in Physical skills the character possesses.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Low Pain Tolerance" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Characters with Low Pain Tolerance are particularly sensitive to pain; they incur a -1 wound modifier for every 2 boxes of cumulative damage, instead of the normal 3 boxes.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Ork Poser" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			Influenced by Goblin Rock or over-hyped orxploitation trends, an Ork Poser is an elf or human character who alters his appearance to appear as an ork. Various cosmetic biomods-tusk implants, steroids, larynx alterations, etc.-allow the character to successfully pass as an ork. Ork posers are an embarrassment to many orks, and an ork who discovers the secret may treat the character with hostility. Other orks, however, might be willing to let the character join the "family"-provided he passes an appropriate hazing ritual to prove his "orkness," of course. An outed ork poser may also face stigma from other humans or elves as "race traitors," if those humans/elves harbor any prejudice against orks. Only humans and elves may take the Ork Poser quality.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Pacifist A" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			The Pacifist quality makes a character unusually principled and humane for the dark streets of 2072. If the quality is taken at 5 BP, the character actively avoids needless violence and will not kill unless in self-defense (and even then, she will do so as humanely as possible). Such characters cannot participate in premeditated murders or wetwork and are compelled to dissuade their fellow shadowrunners from embarking on such operations.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Pacifist B" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			The Pacifist quality makes a character unusually principled and humane for the dark streets of 2072. If the quality is taken at 10 BP, the character has severe moral qualms about any violence and will refuse to harm any living creature that possesses more intelligence than a gnat, regardless of the provocation. If she does, she is overcome by a deep depression, during the onset of which the character refuses to do anything other than eat, sleep and go about her daily routine. Such a state typically lasts several weeks, but may vary at the gamemaster's discretion.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Scorched" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A Scorched character had a nasty experience (or experiences) with Black IC or BTLs in the past, suffering near-permanent effects. The character receives a -2 dice pool modifier to any Willpower-related tests made when facing Black IC or BTLs. This does not include Damage Resistance Tests, but does apply to tests to jack out, log off, resist the effects of Psychotropic IC, or resist addiction.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Scorched H/T" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A Scorched character had a nasty experience (or experiences) with Black IC or BTLs in the past, suffering near-permanent effects. The character receives a -2 dice pool modifier to any Willpower-related tests made when facing Black IC or BTLs. This does not include Damage Resistance Tests, but does apply to tests to jack out, log off, resist the effects of Psychotropic IC, or resist addiction. This quality is for hackers and technomancers.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Sensitive Neural Structure" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with a Sensitive Neural Structure has a particularly delicate nervous system, making him more vulnerable to neural damage from BTLs, Black IC, dumpshock, and other damaging forms of simsense. When resisting damage from Simsense, the character receives a -2 dice pool modifier.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Sensitive Neural Structure H/T" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with a Sensitive Neural Structure has a particularly delicate nervous system, making him more vulnerable to neural damage from BTLs, Black IC, dumpshock, and other damaging forms of simsense. When resisting damage from Simsense, the character receives a -2 dice pool modifier. This quality is for hackers and technomancers.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Sensitive System" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Sensitive System quality has immuno-suppressive problems with implants. Double all Essence losses caused by cyberware implants. This quality does not affect Essence losses for bioware.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Simsense Vertigo" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			Characters who suffer from Simsense Vertigo experience feelings of disorientation whenever they work with augmented reality, virtual reality, and simsense (including smartlinks, simrigs, and image links). Such characters receive an extra -2 dice pool modifier to all tests when interacting with AR, VR, or simsense.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Simsense Vertigo H/T" cost="15">
		<Desc>
			Characters who suffer from Simsense Vertigo experience feelings of disorientation whenever they work with augmented reality, virtual reality, and simsense (including smartlinks, simrigs, and image links). Such characters receive an extra -2 dice pool modifier to all tests when interacting with AR, VR, or simsense. This quality is for hackers and technomancers.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="SINner" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			The character was born with or somehow acquired a legal System Identification Number, or SIN (see Identification, Please, p. 266). This means the character's real identity, personal history, biometric data, credit records, medical history, travel history, etc. are stored and accessible in numerous databanks. This does not mean the character is required to use that SIN, merely that a legal record of him does exist (and may serve as a detriment some day). At 5 BP, the character has a standard SIN and is a bona fide citizen of the nation or extraterritorial megacorp of his choice.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Criminal SINner" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			The character was born with or somehow acquired a legal System Identification Number, or SIN (see Identification, Please, p. 266). This means the character's real identity, personal history, biometric data, credit records, medical history, travel history, etc. are stored and accessible in numerous databanks. This does not mean the character is required to use that SIN, merely that a legal record of him does exist (and may serve as a detriment some day). At 10 BP, the character has a criminal SIN, meaning that the character also has a verifiable criminal record on file, and likely served prison time in the past. As many law enforcement agencies share their data, this means that character is more likely to be identified if linked to a crime.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Spirit Bane" cost="10">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Spirit Bane quality really torques off a certain type of spirit (see Spirits, p. 302). These affected spirits are likely to harass the character when he is in their presence and they may be reluctant to obey or perform favors for the character or his friends. If ordered to attack a party that includes the character, these spirits will single the character out first in an attempt to destroy him. This quality may be taken by any characters, not just magicians, and magicians may possess this quality for a type of spirit that is not part of their magical tradition.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Uncouth" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			Uncouth characters are antisocial or sociopathic and have a difficult time interacting with others. The cost for learning or improving Social skills is twice normal for Uncouth characters (including at character creation), and they may never learn any Social skill groups. Additionally, Uncouth characters are treated as "unaware" in any Social skills that they do not possess at Rating 1 or higher (see Skill Ratings, p. 118). The gamemaster may require the character to make Success Tests for social situations that normal people would have no problems with.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Uneducated" cost="20">
		<Desc>
			An Uneducated character has grown up far away from the modern sprawl and is thus ignorant of modern society in general, possessing only a rudimentary knowledge of reading, writing, and arithmetic. This quality is fitting for characters who grew up in primitive societies or back-to-the-land anti-technological communes (for example, Amazonian primitives, Luddite collectives, or NAN pinkskins). This quality also applies to certain sentient paracritters that have developed their own primitive society (such as shapeshifters, naga, and merrow). Characters with the Uneducated quality are considered "unaware" in Technical, Academic Knowledge, and Professional Knowledge skills they do not possess (see Skill Ratings, p. 118), and they may not default on skill tests for those skills. The gamemaster may also require the character to make Success Tests for ordinary tasks that the typical sprawldweller takes for granted. Additionally, the Karma cost for learning new skills or improving existing ones in these categories is twice normal (including at character creation), and the character may never learn skill groups belonging to these categories.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>
	<NegativeQuality name="Weak Immune System" cost="5">
		<Desc>
			A character with the Weak Immune System quality is more susceptible to infection by disease than normal. The character gains a -2 dice pool modifier to any tests for resisting diseases. Weak Immune System often results from immuno-suppression treatments used in cybersurgery and bio-genetic procedures, so it's reasonable to believe that characters that have undergone extensive body modification are more likely to acquire this quality.
		</Desc>
	</NegativeQuality>	
<!-- End Qualities -->
<!-- Start Skill Groups -->
	<SkillGroup name="None">	
			<Skill name="Archery">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Bows"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Crossbows"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Slingshots"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>Archery governs the use of muscle-powered projectile weapons.</Desc>
			</Skill>	
			<Skill name="Dodge">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Melee Combat"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Ranged Combat"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>Dodge governs your ability to move out of the way of a perceived attack or other incoming threat.</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Exotic Melee Weapon">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Desc>The Exotic Melee Weapon skill must be taken separately for each different weapon you wish to be able to use. Some examples: sais, pole arms, chainsaws, cyber-implant weapons in unusual locations (i.e., elbow spurs, foot blades)..</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Exotic Ranged Weapon">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Desc>Like Exotic Melee Weapon, Exotic Ranged Weapon skill must be taken separately for each different weapon you wish to be able to use. Some examples: lasers, gyrojet pistols, flamethrowers, cyber-implant guns.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Heavy Weapons">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Assault Cannon"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Grenade Launchers"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Guided Missiles"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Machine Guns"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Rocket Launchers"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>The Heavy Weapons skill allows the user to handle ranged projectile and launch weapons larger than an assault rifle, including large weapons when they are mounted on tripods, pintles, gyromounts, or in fixed emplacements (but not in or on vehicles).
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Throwing Weapons">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Lobbed (grenade-style)"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Overhand (baseball-style)"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Shuriken"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Throwing Knives"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>The throwing Weapons skill governs the use of any item thrown by the user.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Arcana">
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Spell Design (by spell category)"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Focus Design (by focus type)"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Ally Spirit Formula"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Free Spirit Formula"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>Arcana governs the practical applications of a tradition's magical theory and the tapping of arcane potency dormant in various materials. Characters use the Arcana skill to develop new spell and magical foci formulae from scratch (rather than learning someone else's tricks) and to produce all types of spirit formulae. Note that Arcana is available to mundanes as well as Awakened. Though they can't put their formulations into practice, non-magical characters can design formulae just as well as magicians.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Assensing">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Aura Reading"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Astral Signatures"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Psychometry"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>Assensing is the skill of learning information from auras, astral forms, and astral signatures (Astral Perception, p. 191). Only characters capable of astral perception (they have the Magician quality or the Adept or Mystic Adept quality and the Astral Perception adept power) may take or use this skill.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Astral Combat">
				<ParentAttribute>Willpower</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Weapon Foci"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Magicians"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Wards"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>The Astral Combat skill is used to fight while in astral space, where normal combat methods are next to useless (Astral Combat, p. 193). Only characters capable of astral perception (they have the Magician quality or the Adept or Mystic Adept quality and the Astral Perception adept power) may take or use this skill.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Enchanting">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Artificing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Alchemy"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Vessel Preparation"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Enchanting comprises the techniques needed to harness the latent magical potency in natural materials and the artificing of magical foci used to assist magic performance. It also includes the creation and preparation of spirit vessels and the evaluation of magical goods. Only characters with the Adept, Magician, or Mystic Adept qualities and a Magic attribute of 1 or more may use this skill.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Diving">
				<ParentAttribute>Body</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Liquid Breathing Apparatus"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mixed Gas"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Oxygen Extraction"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="SCUBA"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Condition"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill covers all forms of underwater diving, including underwater swimming techniques and the use of SCUBA and other underwater gear.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Escape Artist">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Restraint (Ropes, Cuffs, etc.)"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Escape Artist comes into play whenever a character tries to slip out of bonds or shackles without using brute force.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Parachuting">
				<ParentAttribute>Body</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="BASE Jumping"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="HALO"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Low Altitude"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Recreational"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Static Line"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>The Parachuting skill is used when a character exits an aircraft or other high area with a parachute and wishes to stop her quick descent.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Perception">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Hearing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Scent"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Taste"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Touch"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Visual"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
				Perception is used to determine what a character notices about her surroundings that is abnormal or strange.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Instruction">
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Active or Knowledge skill category."></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Instruction Skill allows a character to teach something efficiently to another character.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Intimidation">
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Interrogation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mental"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Physical"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Torture"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill allows a character to make people do what they normally might not, simply out of fear inspired by the character's in-your-face appearance or behavior. Intimidation Tests are opposed by the target's Intimidation + Willpower.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Armorer">
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Armor"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Artillery"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Explosives"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Firearms"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Heavy Weapons"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Weapon Accessories"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to create or repair any weapon or piece of armor for which the character has designs. Armorer also assumes that the character has access to the tools and/or equipment commonly used in that area of expertise. The character still needs time, tools, and materials to build something from scratch. Even a character with a superb level of skill can do little without the proper equipment. If the character is trying to build something new, she also needs theoretical knowledge to design the item, unless someone else provides a detailed blueprint for its construction.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Artisan">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Carpentry"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Guitars"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Painting"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sculpture"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Other Crafts"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Artisan skill represents a number of different creative skills, including singing, painting, and the like. Characters who are well-developed artistically use this skill.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Chemistry">
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Compounds"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Drugs"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Toxins"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Chemistry Technical Active Skill governs the use of and understanding of the properties of matter. It includes proper laboratory procedure and the ability to read chemical formulae.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Demolitions">
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Commercial Explosives"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Defusing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Improvised Explosives"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Plastic Explosives"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Demolitions Skill governs the preparation, measuring, and setting of chemical explosives.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Forgery">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Counterfeiting"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Credstick Forgery"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="False ID"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Image Doctoring"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Paper Forgery"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Those who wish to make a copy of a document or other item use Forgery. Most duplicated items are in the form of art or official paper documents.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Locksmith">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Lock Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Locksmith is the art of manipulating, opening, and repairing mechanical locks.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Gunnery">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Artillery"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Ballistic"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Energy"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Guided Missile"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Rocket"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Gunnery skill governs the use of all vehicle-mounted weapons, whether in mounts, pintles or turrets. This skill includes manual and sensor-enhanced gunnery.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Aerospace">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Deep Space"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Launch Craft"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Remote Operation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Semiballistic"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Suborbital"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to control rocket-boosted parabolic aircraft, suborbital aircraft, and anything that is piloted outside the atmosphere. This includes remote control.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Aircraft">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Remote Operation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Fixed Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Lighter Than Air"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Rotary Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tilt Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Vector Thrust"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Pilot Aircraft governs the use of all aircraft piloted within the atmosphere, including those remotely controlled.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Anthroform">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Remote Operation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Biped"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Quadruped"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to operate any vehicle that walks on legs. It is also used if such operation is remotely controlled.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Exotic Vehicle">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used for exotic vehicles such as undersea sleds, personal lifters, jet packs, hot-air balloons, etc. Each time this skill is taken, a specific exotic vehicle must be chosen to which it applies. This skill is then used whenever piloting that vehicle, whether remotely or in person.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Ground Craft">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Bike"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Hovercraft"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Remote Operation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tracked"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Wheeled"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Characters use Pilot Ground Craft to control ground vehicles without legs, whether remotely or in person.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pilot Watercraft">
				<ParentAttribute>Reaction</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Motorboat"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sail"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Remote Operation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Ship"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Submarine"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Pilot Watercraft is used to control water vehicles both remotely and personally.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Close Combat">		
			<Skill name="Blades">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Axes"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Cyber-Implant Blades"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Knives"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Swords"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Parrying"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Blades skill governs the use of hand-held melee weapons that have a sharpened edge or point. This skill allows a character to use various knives, swords, and axes effectively. This skill is used for cyber-blades implanted in the hands or forearms, but not other areas of the body.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>	
			<Skill name="Clubs">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Batons"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Hammers"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Saps"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Staves"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Parrying"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Clubs governs the use of hand-held melee weapons that have no edge or blade. This skill allows a character to use any blunt, weighted item as a weapon, from a baseball bat to a tire iron to a chair leg.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Unarmed Combat">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Cyber-Implants"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Martial Arts"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Subdual Combat"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Block"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Unarmed Combat skill (also known as hand-to-hand combat) governs the use of combat techniques based solely on the use of the individual's own body parts. In addition to Boxing, this skill covers such combat styles as Oriental martial arts and Brazilian Capoeira. It also covers the use of certain cyber-implants, such as shock hands.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Athletics">		
			<Skill name="Climbing">
				<ParentAttribute>Strength</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Assisted"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Freehand"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Rappelling"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Block"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Condition"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Climbing is used to ascend vertical obstacles or walls, whether using tools or unassisted.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Gymnastics">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Balance"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Breakfall"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Dance"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Jumping"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Parkour"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tumbling"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Gymnastics involves acrobatics feats and balance as well as jumping, vaulting, and tumbling.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Running">
				<ParentAttribute>Strength</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Long Distance"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sprinting"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Urban"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Wilderness"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Running skill is used to increase the distance a character can run, as well as determine how well she can pace herself and conserve energy while running.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Swimming">
				<ParentAttribute>Strength</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Long Distance"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sprinting"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Swimming skill is used to increase the distance a character can swim, and also helps determine how much experience she has had with water.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Stealth">		
			<Skill name="Disguise">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Camoflauge"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Cosmetic"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Theatrical"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Trideo"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					When a character wants to take on a false appearance of some kind, she uses the Disguise skill. This is true whether she wants to look like someone else or blend into the background.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Infiltration">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Urban"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Vehicle"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Wilderdness"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Detection Method"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Infiltration is the skill used when a character wants to sneak around undetected by either other characters or security sensors.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Palming">
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Legerdemain"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Pickpocket"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Shoplifting"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Those who have hands quicker than the eye can see use the Palming skill, which is as much about misdirection as it is dexterous motion. This skill is used to conceal small objects about the character or remove them from others without being noticed.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Shadowing">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Stakeouts"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tail Evasion"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tailing"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Shadowing involves following someone else discreetly without being noticed or ensuring that you are not being followed the same way.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Outdoors">		
			<Skill name="Navigation">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Desert"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Forest"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Jungle"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mountain"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Polar"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Urban"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Maritime"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Other"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill governs a character's ability to determine directions, read maps, plot a course, and stick to it without getting lost.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Survival">
				<ParentAttribute>Willpower</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Desert"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Forest"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Jungle"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mountain"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Polar"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Urban"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Maritime"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Other"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill governs a character's proficiency in surviving outdoors for an extended period of time. It determines her ability with various camping and survival gear, as well as how well she can scrounge for food and water, create makeshift shelters, and adapt to harsh natural conditions.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Tracking">
				<ParentAttribute>Intuition</ParentAttribute>
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Desert"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Forest"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Jungle"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mountain"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Polar"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Urban"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Maritime"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Other"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is a character's ability to track metahumans or critters in the wild. It includes her ability to detect signs of passage, follow a trail, and locate game paths.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Firearms">		
			<Skill name="Automatics">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Assault Rifles"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Carbines"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Machine Pistols"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Submachine Guns"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Automatics skill governs the use of personal firearms larger than a pistol, capable of autofire,but typically with a shorter barrel than a longarm.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>	
			<Skill name="Longarms">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Shotguns"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sniper Rifles"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sporting Rifles"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill governs the use of all personal firearms with extended barrels, especially those designed to be used braced against the shoulder.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Pistols">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Agility</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Holdouts"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Revolvers"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Semi-Automatics"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tasers"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Pistols skill governs the use of all types of hand-held firearms, including holdouts, light and heavy pistols, and tasers.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Conjuring">		
			<Skill name="Banishing">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Air"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Fire"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Water"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Earth"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Magicians use the Banishing skill to disrupt spirits, removing them from the physical and astral planes.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Binding">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Air"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Fire"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Water"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Earth"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Binding skill is used to ask/demand long-term services from a spirit the magician has already summoned.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Summoning">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Air"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Fire"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Water"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Spirits of Earth"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to summon spirits and determines how many services they owe you.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Sorcery">		
			<Skill name="Counterspelling">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Combat Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Detection Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Manipulation Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Health Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Illusion Spells"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Magicians use the Counterspelling skill to remove existing sustained spells from people or objects, or defend against spells cast at them or others.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Ritual Spellcasting">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Combat Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Detection Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Manipulation Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Health Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Illusion Spells"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Ritual Spellcasting skill is used to cast spells in a ritual fashion (Ritual Spellcasting, p. 184). In those cases, Ritual Spellcasting is used instead of Spellcasting to determine the results.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Spellcasting">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Magic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Combat Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Detection Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Manipulation Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Health Spells"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Illusion Spells"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Spellcasting skill governs the control of magical energy in the form of spells.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Tasking">		
			<Skill name="Compiling">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Resonance</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Sprite Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to create sprites and determines how many tasks they owe you.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Decompiling">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Resonance</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Sprite Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to decompile sprites.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Resonance">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Resonance</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Sprite Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill is used to register sprites for long-term service.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Influence">		
			<Skill name="Con">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Fast Talk"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Impersonation"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Seduction"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Characters using the Con skill are misrepresenting the truth in some way and trying to get someone else to believe them. This may be flat out lying, evasion, or double talk, but the intended result is to have the target believe something that is false. Con Tests are opposed by the target's Con (or Negotiation) + Intuition.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Etiquette">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="High Society"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Street Gang"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Mafia"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Corporate"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Media"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By culture or subculture."></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Etiquette Skill allows a character to function within a specific subculture without appearing out of place. It allows the character to fit in, put suspicious or agitated people at ease, and defuse tense social situations. It also allows the player to negate a social gaffe she made that the character wouldn't have.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Leadership">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Gut Check"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Morale"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Persuasion"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Strategy"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tactics"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Leadership Skill governs a character's ability to get others to do her bidding through the exercise of example and authority. It includes an aspect of problem-solving, but is not intended to substitute for clear thinking and good planning on the part of the players. Leadership Tests are opposed by the target's Leadership + Charisma.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Negotiation">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Charisma</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Bargaining"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Diplomacy"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sense Motive"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Negotiation Skill governs the psychology and bargaining tactics used when the character deals with another and seeks to come out ahead, either through careful and deliberate bartering or throughfast talk. It is opposed by the target's Negotiation + Charisma. Negotiation can also be used to determine if a character has noticed if someone is lying to them.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Mechanic">		
			<Skill name="Aeronautics Mechanic">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Aerospace"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Fixed Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Lighter Than Air"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Rotary Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tilt Wing"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Vector Thrust"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Characters with this skill can repair and maintain aircraft. The proper tools and time are still necessary.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Automotive Mechanic">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Anthroform"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Hover"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Wheeled"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Tracked"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Automotive Mechanic skill is used to repair and maintain ground craft of all kinds. The proper tools and time are still necessary.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Industrial Mechanic">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Electrical Power Systems"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Hydraulics"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Robotics"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Structural"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Welding"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Industrial Mechanic skill is used to repair and maintain mechanical devices used in various industries and teaches a baseline of mechanics ability. The proper tools and time are still necessary.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Nautical Mechanic">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Motorboat"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sailboat"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Submarine"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Ship"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Nautical Mechanic skill is used to repair and maintain watercraft of all kinds. The proper tools and time are still necessary.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>

	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Cracking">		
			<Skill name="Cybercombat">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Specific Opponents"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Cybercombat skill is used to attack other icons in the Matrix, utilizing attack programs and system tricks.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Electronic Warfare">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Communications"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Encryption"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Jamming"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Sensor Operations"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Electronic Warfare is used to disrupt communications in a variety of ways, such as jamming, signal degradation, or complete overtaking of control of a target's communication systems. It is also used for encoding and decoding communications. Appropriate equipment is necessary to make use of this skill.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Hacking">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Program"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Device Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Hacking skill is used to exploit and subvert the programming of computers and electronics, specifically Matrix systems and interactions.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Electronics">		
			<Skill name="Computer">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Program"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Device Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Computer skill governs the use and understanding of computers and electronic devices, which in the 2070s is just about everything powered by electricity. It does not include knowledge of exploiting or subverting such systems, which is covered by the Hacking (software) or Hardware skills.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Data Search">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Source"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="By Data Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This is the character's research ability, her ability to use search engines, databases and other tools to track down information online or in computer storage. Data Search includes the character's ability to refine search parameters as well as her knowledge of lesser known archives and resources.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Hardware">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Specific Type"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					This skill governs the creation, repair, and technical manipulation of computers and electronic devices. To create something, a plan, the proper materials, and time are still needed.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Software">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Defensive Utilities"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Offensive Utilities"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Masking Utilities"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Operational Utilities"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Special Utilities (specify)"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The Software skill comes into play when a character is writing utilities for use in the Matrix.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
	<SkillGroup name="Biotech">		
			<Skill name="Cybertechnology">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Bioware"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Bodyware"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Cyberlimbs"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Headware"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Nanoware"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Cybertechnology is the ability to create and care for cybernetics and bioware, possessed primarily by inventors, medical professionals, and cyberdocs. This skill also includes knowledge about the current state of the field of cybertechnology and the ability to repair damaged cyberware. A proper facility and the right materials are needed to manufacture cyberware.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="First Aid">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="By Type of Treatment"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					The First Aid skill governs basic medicine in a hands-on sense, as a paramedic rather than a physician. This skill provides little knowledge of cybernetics and how they function, and cannot be used to repair them.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
			<Skill name="Medicine">
				<SkillType>Active</SkillType>
				<ParentAttribute>Logic</ParentAttribute>
				<Specializations>
					<Specialization name ="Cosmetic Surgery"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Extended Care"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Implant Surgery"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Magical Health"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Organ Culture"></Specialization>
					<Specialization name ="Trauma Surgery"></Specialization>
				</Specializations>
				<Desc>
					Medicine is the skill used for more detailed attempts at helping a character medically, beyond what mere First Aid can do. It includes the proper treatment of disease and illness as well as wounds. Medicine interacts with cybernetics only when they are being implanted into a body or removed from one.
				</Desc>
			</Skill>
	</SkillGroup>
<!-- End Skill Groups -->
<!-- Start Metatypes -->
	<Metatype name ="Human">
		<BPCost>0</BPCost>
		<Attributes>
			<MetaAttribute name="Body">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Agility">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Reaction">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Strength">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Charisma">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Intuition">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Logic">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Willpower">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Initiative">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>12</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>18</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaSpecialAttribute name="Edge">
				<Start>2</Start>		
			</MetaSpecialAttribute>
		</Attributes>
		<Desc>Humans make up the statistical standard. As characters, their only statistical bonus is to the Edge attribute (p. 67).
		</Desc>
	</Metatype>
	<Metatype name ="Ork">
		<BPCost>20</BPCost>
		<Attributes>
			<MetaAttribute name="Body">
				<Start> 4</Start>
				<NaturalMax>9</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>13</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Agility">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Reaction">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Strength">
				<Start> 3</Start>
				<NaturalMax>8</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>12</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Charisma">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Intuition">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Logic">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Willpower">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Initiative">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>12</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>18</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
		</Attributes>
		<SpecialAbilities>
			<Ability name="Low-Light Vision"></Ability>		
		</SpecialAbilities>
		<Desc>Orks are much tougher (much higher Body), stronger (higher Strength), less charismatic (lower Charisma), and less acute (lower Logic) than humans. They too have low-light vision.</Desc>
	</Metatype>
	<Metatype name ="Dwarf">
		<BPCost>25</BPCost>
		<Attributes>
			<MetaAttribute name="Body">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>7</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>10</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Agility">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Reaction">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Strength">
				<Start> 3</Start>
				<NaturalMax>8</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>12</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Charisma">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Intuition">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Logic">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Willpower">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>7</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>10</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Initiative">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>11</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>16</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
		</Attributes>
		<SpecialAbilities>
			<Ability name="Thermographic Vision"></Ability>
			<Ability name="+2 dice to Body Tests to resist pathogens and toxins."></Ability>
		</SpecialAbilities>
		<Desc>Dwarfs are hardier (slightly higher Body), stronger (higher Strength), and more stubborn (higher Willpower) than humans, but are also slower on the draw (lower Reaction). They have thermographic vision, which allows them to see radiated infrared (heat) energy as well as the normal light spectrum simultaneously. They have a slower movement rate than other metatypes, but are more resistant to disease. And yes, they are short.</Desc>
	</Metatype>
	<Metatype name ="Elf">
		<BPCost>30</BPCost>
		<Attributes>
			<MetaAttribute name="Body">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Agility">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>7</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>10</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Reaction">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Strength">
				<Start> 3</Start>
				<NaturalMax>8</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>12</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Charisma">
				<Start> 3</Start>
				<NaturalMax>8</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>12</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Intuition">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Logic">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Willpower">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Initiative">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>12</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>18</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
		</Attributes>
		<SpecialAbilities>
			<Ability name="Low-Light Vision"></Ability>		
		</SpecialAbilities>
		<Desc>Elves are more agile (higher Agility) and more charismatic (higher Charisma) than humans. They also have low-light vision, which enables them to see clearly in near-total darkness.</Desc>
	</Metatype>
	<Metatype name ="Troll">
		<BPCost>40</BPCost>
		<Attributes>
			<MetaAttribute name="Body">
				<Start> 5</Start>
				<NaturalMax>10</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>15</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Agility">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Reaction">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Strength">
				<Start> 5</Start>
				<NaturalMax>10</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>15</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Charisma">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>4</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>6</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Intuition">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Logic">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>5</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>7</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Willpower">
				<Start> 1</Start>
				<NaturalMax>6</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>9</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
			<MetaAttribute name="Initiative">
				<Start> 2</Start>
				<NaturalMax>11</NaturalMax>
				<AugmentedMax>16</AugmentedMax>
			</MetaAttribute>
		</Attributes>
		<SpecialAbilities>
			<Ability name="Thermographic Vision"></Ability>	
			<Ability name="+1 natural armor (cumulative with worn armor)"></Ability>	
			<Ability name="+1 to Reach"></Ability>			
		</SpecialAbilities>
		<Desc>Trolls are big and nasty. They are a lot tougher (much higher Body), less agile (lower Agility), much stronger (higher Strength), less charismatic (lower Charisma), less perceptive (lower Intuition), and less acute (lower Logic) than humans. They have thermographic vision, really long arms that give them advantages in melee combat, and extremely tough skin with bony deposits that makes them more resistant to damage.</Desc>
	</Metatype>
<!-- End Metatypes -->
<!-- Start Spells -->
	<Spell name="Acid Stream (Indirect, Elemental)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create a powerful corrosive that sprays the target, causing terrible burns and eating away organic and metallic material-treat it as Acid damage (p. 163), with appropriate effects on the affected area and any objects therein. The acid quickly evaporates in the turn following the spell's casting, but the damage done remains. Acid Stream is a single-target spell, while Toxic Wave is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Toxic Wave (Indirect, Elemental, Area)" type="Combat">
			<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 5
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create a powerful corrosive that sprays the target, causing terrible burns and eating away organic and metallic material-treat it as Acid damage (p. 163), with appropriate effects on the affected area and any objects therein. The acid quickly evaporates in the turn following the spell's casting, but the damage done remains. Acid Stream is a single-target spell, while Toxic Wave is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Punch (Indirect, Touch)" type="Combat">

			<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells smack the target(s) with invisible psychokinetic force, similar to a bruising punch, that inflicts Stun damage. Clout affects a single target, Blast is an area spell. Punch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Clout (Indirect)" type="Combat">
			<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells smack the target(s) with invisible psychokinetic force, similar to a bruising punch, that inflicts Stun damage. Clout affects a single target, Blast is an area spell. Punch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
			<Spell name="Blast (Indirect, Area)" type="Combat">
			<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells smack the target(s) with invisible psychokinetic force, similar to a bruising punch, that inflicts Stun damage. Clout affects a single target, Blast is an area spell. Punch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Death Touch (Direct, Touch)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Death Touch, Manabolt, and Manaball all channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. As mana spells, they only affect living and magical targets and are resisted by Willpower. Manabolt affects a single target, Manaball is an area spell. Death Touch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Manabolt (Direct)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Death Touch, Manabolt, and Manaball all channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. As mana spells, they only affect living and magical targets and are resisted by Willpower. Manabolt affects a single target, Manaball is an area spell. Death Touch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Manaball (Direct, Area)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Death Touch, Manabolt, and Manaball all channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. As mana spells, they only affect living and magical targets and are resisted by Willpower. Manabolt affects a single target, Manaball is an area spell. Death Touch requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Flamethrower (Indirect, Elemental)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create an explosion of flames that flash into existence and scorch the target(s). These spells deal Fire damage (p. 164). These flames burn out after striking the target, but their secondary effects may ignite flammable materials that will continue to burn after the spell is exhausted. Flamethrower is a single target spell, while Fireball is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Fireball (Indirect, Elemental, Area)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 5
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create an explosion of flames that flash into existence and scorch the target(s). These spells deal Fire damage (p. 164). These flames burn out after striking the target, but their secondary effects may ignite flammable materials that will continue to burn after the spell is exhausted. Flamethrower is a single target spell, while Fireball is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Lightning Bolt (Indirect, Elemental)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create and direct vicious strikes of electricity that cause Electricity damage (p. 163). Lightning Bolt is a single target spell. Ball Lightning is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Ball Lightning (Indirect, Elemental, Area)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 5
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create and direct vicious strikes of electricity that cause Electricity damage (p. 163). Lightning Bolt is a single target spell. Ball Lightning is an area spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Shatter (Direct, Touch)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. They affect both living and non-living targets and are resisted by the target's Body. Powerbolt affects a single target. Powerball is an area spell. Shatter requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Powerbolt (Direct)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. They affect both living and non-living targets and are resisted by the target's Body. Powerbolt affects a single target. Powerball is an area spell. Shatter requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Powerball (Direct, Area)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: P &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel destructive magical power into the target, doing Physical damage. They affect both living and non-living targets and are resisted by the target's Body. Powerbolt affects a single target. Powerball is an area spell. Shatter requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Knockout (Direct, Touch)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel magical energy directly into the target, causing Stun damage. They are often referred to as "sleep" spells because they can render targets unconscious. Stunbolt affects a single target. Stunball is an area spell. Knockout requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Stunbolt (Direct)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel magical energy directly into the target, causing Stun damage. They are often referred to as "sleep" spells because they can render targets unconscious. Stunbolt affects a single target. Stunball is an area spell. Knockout requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Stunball (Direct, Area)" type="Combat">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Damage: S &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells channel magical energy directly into the target, causing Stun damage. They are often referred to as "sleep" spells because they can render targets unconscious. Stunbolt affects a single target. Stunball is an area spell. Knockout requires the caster to touch the target.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Analyze Device (Active, Directional)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell allows the subject to analyze the purpose and operation of a device or piece of equipment within range of the sense. The caster must	gain enough hits on the Spellcasting Test to beat the item's Object Resistance (p. 183). Each net hit gives the subject a bonus die while operating the device, and allows the subject to ignore any skill defaulting modifiers for using the device while the spell is sustained.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>	
	<Spell name="Analyze Truth (Active, Directional)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can tell whether a target's statements are the truth. Halftruths or falsehoods the target believes to be true are not detected by this spell. The spell needs at least 1 net hit to determine validity. The spell does not work on written materials or through any sort of technological medium. The subject must hear a statement in person (with the target within range) to know whether it is true.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>		
	<Spell name="Clairaudience (Passive, Directional)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) -1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can hear distant sounds as if physically present at a chosen point within the sensory range of the spell. The "listening point" may be moved to any other point within range of the spell. While using clairaudience, the subject cannot use her normal hearing. This spell does not translate visual images, only sounds (and only sounds within the subject's natural range of hearing; augmented hearing does not apply).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>		
	<Spell name="Clairvoyance (Passive, Directional)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) -1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can see distant scenes as if physically present at a chosen point within the sensory range of the spell. The "visual point" may be moved to any other point within range of the spell. The subject cannot use normal vision or astral perception while using it. This spell does not translate sound, only vision. Any augmented vision possessed by the subject does not function through this spell, nor does astral perception. Magicians cannot use clairvoyance to target others with spells.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>		
	<Spell name="Combat Sense (Active, Psychic)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can subconsciously analyze combat and other dangerous situations within range, sensing events a split-second before they happen. Every hit on the Spellcasting Test adds 1 die for Reaction on Surprise Tests and when defending against ranged and melee attacks for the duration of the spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Enemies (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can detect living targets within range who have hostile intentions toward him. The spell does not detect traps (since they are not alive), nor can it detect someone about to shoot into a crowd at random (the hostility is not directed at the subject of the spell). The spell can detect targets preparing an ambush or other surprise attack.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Enemies, Extended (Active, Extended Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can detect living targets within range who have hostile intentions toward him. The spell does not detect traps (since they are not alive), nor can it detect someone about to shoot into a crowd at random (the hostility is not directed at the subject of the spell). The spell can detect targets preparing an ambush or other surprise attack.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>		
	<Spell name="Detect Individual (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can detect the presence of a particular individual anywhere within range of the sense. The magician names the individual during casting; she must know the target or have met him in the past.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Life (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject detects all living beings (but not spirits) within range of the sense and knows their number and relative location. In a crowded area, the spell is virtually useless, picking up a blurred mass of traces.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Life, Extended (Active, Extended Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) +2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject detects all living beings (but not spirits) within range of the sense and knows their number and relative location. In a crowded area, the spell is virtually useless, picking up a blurred mass of traces.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect [Life Form] (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) -1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject detects all of a specified type of life form within the range of the sense and knows their number and relative location. Each different life form requires a separate spell (Detect Orks, Detect Elves, Detect Dragons, and so forth).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect [Life Form], Extended (Active, Extended Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) +1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject detects all of a specified type of life form within the range of the sense and knows their number and relative location. Each different life form requires a separate spell (Detect Orks, Detect Elves, Detect Dragons, and so forth).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Magic (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can detect the presence of all foci, spells, wards, magical lodges, and spirits within range of the sense. It does not detect Awakened characters or critters, astral signatures, or the effects of permanent spells once they have become permanent.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect Magic, Extended (Active, Extended Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject can detect the presence of all foci, spells, wards, magical lodges, and spirits within range of the sense. It does not detect Awakened characters or critters, astral signatures, or the effects of permanent spells once they have become permanent.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detect [Object] (Active, Area)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) -1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The subject detects all of a specified type of object within range of the sense and knows their number and relative location. Each type of object requires a separate spell (Detect Guns, Detect Computers, Detect Explosives, and so forth).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mindlink (Active, Psychic)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Mindlink allows the caster and one voluntary subject to communicate mentally, exchanging conversation, emotions, and mental images. One hit on the Spellcasting Test is enough to establish the link. The subject must remain within range of the spellcaster for the Mindlink to work.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mind Probe (Active, Directional)" type="Detection">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell allows the subject to telepathically probe the mind of a specific target within range of the sense (chosen when the spell is cast). The target is aware of the probing, though they may not know the source of the spell. If the caster gains one or more net hits, consult the Mind Probe Results table for the information gained. The subject may probe for one piece of information per Complex Action. Additional uses of Mind Probe against the same target within a number of hours equal to the target's Willpower are at a -2 dice pool modifier per previous Spellcasting attempt.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Antidote" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Toxin DV) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell helps a poisoned subject to overcome a toxin. It must be applied before the toxin does damage (though an Antidote spell applied afterward may alleviate some side effects, if the gamemaster chooses). The poisoned character receives a number of additional dice on her Toxin Resistance Test (p. 254) equal to the net hits.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Cure Disease" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Disease DV) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell is used at any point after infection to help a patient overcome illness. The infected character receives a number of additional dice on her Disease Resistance Test equal to the spell's net hits. It does not heal any damage already inflicted by the disease (that takes a separate Healing spell).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Decrease [Attribute] (Negative)" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell weakens the target by decreasing a chosen attribute. A version of this spell exists for each Physical and Mental attribute, but not for Special attributes (Initiative, Edge, Essence, Magic, or Resonance). It affects both natural and augmented attributes. The target resists the spell using the attribute affected. If the caster wins, the attribute is reduced by the spell's net hits. If a Physical attribute is reduced to 0, the victim is incapacitated or paralyzed. If a Mental attribute is reduced to 0, the victim stands about mindlessly confused. Note that decreasing an attribute may affect other derived statistics (Decrease Intuition also affects Initiative, for example, while Decrease Willpower will remove boxes from the character's Stun Condition Monitor for as long as the spell lasts).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Detox" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Toxin DV) - 4
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Detox relieves the side effects of a drug or poison. The Force of the spell must equal or exceed the toxin's base DV. A single net hit is sufficient to eliminate all symptoms. Detox does not heal or prevent damage done by toxins, but it eliminates any side effects they may have on the victim (dizziness, hallucinations, nausea, pain, and so forth). Detox is the hangover cure of choice among those who can afford it.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Heal" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Damage Value) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Heal repairs physical injuries. It heals a number of boxes of Physical damage equal to the spell's hits from the Spellcasting Test. Hits can also be used to reduce the base time for the spell to become permanent; each hit spent this way shaves off 1 Combat Turn (hits can be split between healing and reducing time as the caster desires). A character can only be magically healed once for any single set of injuries.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Hibernate" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The caster must touch a voluntary or unconscious subject. The spell puts the subject in a form of suspended animation. The subject's bodily processes are slowed by a factor equal to the hits. For example, If 4 hits were scored, the subject's metabolism is slowed by a factor of 4. Such a subject sealed into a chamber with enough air to keep it alive for a day would be able to last four days.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Increase [Attribute]" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell increases an attribute (natural or augmented) on a voluntary subject. A version of this spell exists for each Physical and Mental attribute, but not for Special attributes (Initiative, Edge, Essence, Magic, or Resonance). The Force of the spell must equal or exceed the (augmented) value of the attribute being affected. The attribute is increased by an amount equal to the hits scored. Each attribute can only be affected by a single Increase Attribute spell at a time. Note that increasing an attribute may affect other derived statistics (Increase Reaction also affects Initiative, for example, while Increase Body will add extra boxes to the character's Physical Condition Monitor for as long as the spell lasts).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Increase Reflexes" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell increases the reflexes (Initiative and Initiative Passes) of a voluntary subject. Each level of increase adds +1 Initiative and +1 Initiative Pass. The caster must achieve a certain threshold for each level: Threshold 2: +1 Initiative, + 1 Initiative Pass. Threshold 3: +2 Initiative, + 2 Initiative Passes. Threshold 4 (max.): +3 Initiative, + 3 Initiative Passes. A character can only be affected by a single Increase Reflexes spell at a time; the maximum IPs any character can have is 4.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Oxygenate" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell oxygenates the blood of a voluntary subject, providing extra Body dice (1 die for every hit) to resist suffocation, strangulation, the effects of inhaled gas, or any other effect of oxygen deprivation. The spell also allows the subject to breathe underwater.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Prophylaxis" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell provides additional dice (+1 die per hit) for a voluntary subject to resist infection, drugs, or toxins. The spell does not discriminate between harmful and beneficial drugs, so the subject also resists medicines and other helpful drugs while under the effects of the spell. Reduce the effect of a beneficial drug by 1 for every hit of the spell. Two or more hits prevent the subject from being affected by alcohol while under the effect of this spell.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
		<Spell name="Resist Pain" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Damage Value) - 4
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Resist Pain allows the subject to ignore the pain of injuries, reducing the penalties from Physical or Stun damage. Each hit on the Spellcasting Test removes the effect of one box of damage from each of the subject's Condition Monitor tracks. It does not remove the damage itself, only eliminates the modifiers. Resist Pain can only be used once on any given set of injuries. If all of the boxes on the track are filled, the character still falls unconscious. The spell is "permanent" in that the boost to the patient's endorphin levels does not wear off. If the subject's damage rises above the level at which the patient is resisting pain or if the existing injuries heal, the spell dissipates.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
		<Spell name="Stabilize" type="Health">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (Overfl ow damage) - 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			When applied to a character with a filled Physical damage track, this spell stabilizes all vital functions and prevents the character from dying. The spell's Force must equal or exceed the overflow damage already taken when the spell starts. The full time must be taken for the spell to become Permanent (p. 203) before the character is stabilized; hits reduce the time it takes by 1 Combat Turn each. If successful, the spell prevents the character from taking further damage from Physical Damage Overflow (p. 253).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Confusion (Realistic, Multi-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells produce a storm of conflicting sensations and images to confuse the senses. For each net hit on the Spellcasting Test, the target suffers a -1 dice pool modifier to all tests from the distraction. Confusion affects a single target. Mass Confusion is an area spell. The Chaos spell is a physical version of Confusion (above), so it also affects technological systems and sensing devices. Chaotic World is an area version of Chaos.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mass Confusion (Realistic, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells produce a storm of conflicting sensations and images to confuse the senses. For each net hit on the Spellcasting Test, the target suffers a -1 dice pool modifier to all tests from the distraction. Confusion affects a single target. Mass Confusion is an area spell. The Chaos spell is a physical version of Confusion (above), so it also affects technological systems and sensing devices. Chaotic World is an area version of Chaos.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Chaos (Realistic, Multi-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells produce a storm of conflicting sensations and images to confuse the senses. For each net hit on the Spellcasting Test, the target suffers a -1 dice pool modifier to all tests from the distraction. Confusion affects a single target. Mass Confusion is an area spell. The Chaos spell is a physical version of Confusion (above), so it also affects technological systems and sensing devices. Chaotic World is an area version of Chaos.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Chaotic World (Realistic, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells produce a storm of conflicting sensations and images to confuse the senses. For each net hit on the Spellcasting Test, the target suffers a -1 dice pool modifier to all tests from the distraction. Confusion affects a single target. Mass Confusion is an area spell. The Chaos spell is a physical version of Confusion (above), so it also affects technological systems and sensing devices. Chaotic World is an area version of Chaos.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Entertainment (Obvious, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These area spells create obvious, but entertaining, illusions. Hits on the Spellcasting Test measure how creative, interesting, and captivating the audience finds the illusion. The caster can reproduce just about anything from her imagination, or re-create something she has experienced. The gamemaster might require additional hits for exacting detail. Entertainment affects the minds of the subjects and cannot be detected by non-living sensors. Trid Entertainment is a physical spell, and can be perceived by both living subjects and non-living sensors. These spells are used for amusement as well as art. The entertainment industry uses illusionists as literal "special effects wizards." Magical designers and artists work to create new and interesting sensations, including sensations that can't otherwise be experienced in the real world. Only the wealthy can afford the unique experiences offered by such spellcasters firsthand.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Trid Entertainment (Obvious, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These area spells create obvious, but entertaining, illusions. Hits on the Spellcasting Test measure how creative, interesting, and captivating the audience finds the illusion. The caster can reproduce just about anything from her imagination, or re-create something she has experienced. The gamemaster might require additional hits for exacting detail. Entertainment affects the minds of the subjects and cannot be detected by non-living sensors. Trid Entertainment is a physical spell, and can be perceived by both living subjects and non-living sensors. These spells are used for amusement as well as art. The entertainment industry uses illusionists as literal "special effects wizards." Magical designers and artists work to create new and interesting sensations, including sensations that can't otherwise be experienced in the real world. Only the wealthy can afford the unique experiences offered by such spellcasters firsthand. Invisibility (Realistic, Single-Sense)
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Invisibility (Realistic, Single-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell makes the subject more diffcult to detect by normal visual senses (including low-light, thermographic, and other senses that rely on the visual spectrum). The subject is completely tangible and detectable by the other senses (hearing, smell, touch, etc.). Her aura is still visible to astral perception. Anyone who might perceive the subject must first successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Even if the spell is resisted, the subject might remain unnoticed if she wins a Shadowing or Infiltration Test. An invisible character may still be detected by non-visual means, such as hearing or smell. Attacks against invisible targets suffer the Target Hidden modifier (p. 150) if the attacker is unable to see or otherwise sense the subject of the spell. Invisibility affects the minds of viewers. Improved invisibility creates an actual warping of light around the subject that affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Improved Invisibility (Realistic, Single-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell makes the subject more diffcult to detect by normal visual senses (including low-light, thermographic, and other senses that rely on the visual spectrum). The subject is completely tangible and detectable by the other senses (hearing, smell, touch, etc.). Her aura is still visible to astral perception. Anyone who might perceive the subject must first successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Even if the spell is resisted, the subject might remain unnoticed if she wins a Shadowing or Infiltration Test. An invisible character may still be detected by non-visual means, such as hearing or smell. Attacks against invisible targets suffer the Target Hidden modifier (p. 150) if the attacker is unable to see or otherwise sense the subject of the spell. Invisibility affects the minds of viewers. Improved invisibility creates an actual warping of light around the subject that affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mask (Realistic, Multi-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The Mask spell requires the caster to touch the subject. The subject assumes a different physical appearance (of the same basic size and shape) chosen by the caster. This alters the subject's voice, scent, and other physical characteristics as well. Anyone who might see through the disguise must first successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Mask affects the minds of viewers. Physical Mask creates an illusion that affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Physical Mask (Realistic, Multi-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: T &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The Mask spell requires the caster to touch the subject. The subject assumes a different physical appearance (of the same basic size and shape) chosen by the caster. This alters the subject's voice, scent, and other physical characteristics as well. Anyone who might see through the disguise must first successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Mask affects the minds of viewers. Physical Mask creates an illusion that affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Phantasm (Realistic, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) +2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These area spells create convincing illusions of any object, creature, or scene the caster desires. They can create an illusion of anything the caster has seen before, from a flower or a credstick to a dragon breathing fire, as long as the illusion is no larger than the spell's area. Anyone who might pierce the illusion must successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Phantasm only affects living beings, while Trid Phantasm affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Trid Phantasm (Realistic, Multi-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) +3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These area spells create convincing illusions of any object, creature, or scene the caster desires. They can create an illusion of anything the caster has seen before, from a flower or a credstick to a dragon breathing fire, as long as the illusion is no larger than the spell's area. Anyone who might pierce the illusion must successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Phantasm only affects living beings, while Trid Phantasm affects technological sensors as well.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Hush (Realistic, Single-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create an area that damps sound. Sonic attacks into or out of the field, as well as critter powers using a sonic medium (such as Paralyzing Howl), are reduced by -1 per hit on the Spellcasting Test. Anyone attempting to hear a sound from within or across the silenced area must successfully resist the spell.Hush is a mana spell and so only affects living beings and magic sonic attacks. Silence affects technological devices and is useful for jamming alarms, detection devices, sonar, and tactical communications, as well as technological sonic weapons.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Silence (Realistic, Single-Sense, Area)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			These spells create an area that damps sound. Sonic attacks into or out of the field, as well as critter powers using a sonic medium (such as Paralyzing Howl), are reduced by -1 per hit on the Spellcasting Test. Anyone attempting to hear a sound from within or across the silenced area must successfully resist the spell.Hush is a mana spell and so only affects living beings and magic sonic attacks. Silence affects technological devices and is useful for jamming alarms, detection devices, sonar, and tactical communications, as well as technological sonic weapons.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Stealth (Realistic, Single-Sense)" type="Illusion">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) +1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Stealth makes the subject less audible to normal hearing (including augmented hearing). The subject moves in silence, making less or no noise. Things not directly touched by the subject can still make noise, so a character under a Stealth spell would make no noise knocking on a door, but the door would make noise hitting the floor or wall if it was kicked in. Anyone who might hear the subject must first successfully resist the spell. Simply make one Spellcasting Test and use the hits scored as the threshold for anyone that resists at a later point. Even if the spell is resisted, the subject might remain unnoticed if she wins a Shadowing or Infiltration Test.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Armor (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell creates a glowing field of magical energy around the subject that protects against Physical damage. It provides both Ballistic and Impact armor (cumulative with worn armor) to the subject equal to the hits scored.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Control Actions (Mental)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The caster of this spell controls the physical actions of a target like a puppeteer pulling strings. The victim's consciousness is unaffected, but the caster controls the victim's body. The target uses any skills or abilities at the caster's orders, but these tests suffer a dice pool modifier equal to the target's Willpower because of the victim's resistance to the caster's commands. Controlling a target character requires the caster to spend a Simple Action; when not directly controlled, the victim may act as normal. Control Actions only affects a single target, Mob Control affects any living targets within the area of effect. Victims of a Mob Control may be manipulated individually (with separate Simple Actions) or issued the same command as a group (with a single Simple Action).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mob Control (Mental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The caster of this spell controls the physical actions of a target like a puppeteer pulling strings. The victim's consciousness is unaffected, but the caster controls the victim's body. The target uses any skills or abilities at the caster's orders, but these tests suffer a dice pool modifier equal to the target's Willpower because of the victim's resistance to the caster's commands. Controlling a target character requires the caster to spend a Simple Action; when not directly controlled, the victim may act as normal. Control Actions only affects a single target, Mob Control affects any living targets within the area of effect. Victims of a Mob Control may be manipulated individually (with separate Simple Actions) or issued the same command as a group (with a single Simple Action).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Control Emotions (Mental)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The target feels an overwhelming emotion chosen by the spellcaster (such as love, hate, fear, joy, sorrow, and so forth). The target believes the emotion wholeheartedly, but not mindlessly. A target who acts in accordance with the emotion (for example, fighting while filled with anger or hate) suffers no penalty. If the target takes action not relevant to the emotion (trying to drive while laughing hysterically), she suffers a -2 dice pool modifier for the distraction. The caster may switch emotions with a Simple Action. Control Emotions only affects a single target, Mob Mood affects any living targets within the area of effect.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mob Mood (Mental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The target feels an overwhelming emotion chosen by the spellcaster (such as love, hate, fear, joy, sorrow, and so forth). The target believes the emotion wholeheartedly, but not mindlessly. A target who acts in accordance with the emotion (for example, fighting while filled with anger or hate) suffers no penalty. If the target takes action not relevant to the emotion (trying to drive while laughing hysterically), she suffers a -2 dice pool modifier for the distraction. The caster may switch emotions with a Simple Action. Control Emotions only affects a single target, Mob Mood affects any living targets within the area of effect.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Control Thoughts (Mental)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The caster seizes control of the target's mind, directing everything the target does. The caster mentally gives commands with a Simple Action and the target is compelled to obey. Control thoughts affects a single target, while Mob Mind affects any living targets within the area of effect. Victims of a Mob Mind may be manipulated individually (with separate Simple Actions) or issued the same command as a group (with a single Simple Action).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mob Mind (Mental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 4
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The caster seizes control of the target's mind, directing everything the target does. The caster mentally gives commands with a Simple Action and the target is compelled to obey. Control thoughts affects a single target, while Mob Mind affects any living targets within the area of effect. Victims of a Mob Mind may be manipulated individually (with separate Simple Actions) or issued the same command as a group (with a single Simple Action).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
		<Spell name="Fling (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell psychokinetically hurls a single object of no more than (Force) kilograms at a designated target with a Strength equal to onehalf the spellcaster's Magic. Treat the Spellcasting Test as a normal Ranged Combat Test for the purposes of the item hitting the target. Throwing weapons propelled by this spell use their normal range based on the spell's effective Strength.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
		<Spell name="Ice Sheet (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: I &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell creates a slippery sheet of ice over the area of effect. Characters crossing the ice must make an Agility + Reaction Test with a threshold equal to the hits scored to avoid falling prone. Vehicles must make a Crash Test (p. 178). The sheet melts at a rate of 1 square meter per minute in normal temperatures.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Ignite (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2)
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			The Ignite spell accelerates molecular motion in the target, causing it to catch fire once the spell becomes permanent. The spellcaster must achieve enough net hits to beat a threshold equal to the target's Object Resistance (p. 183). Once the target ignites, it burns normally until it is consumed or extinguished. Against living targets, treat Ignite as an Opposed Test pitting Spellcasting + Magic vs. Body (+ Counterspelling). If successful, Ignite wraps a living target in heat and flames once it has been made permanent, causing (Force) boxes of Fire damage (p. 164) on the first Combat Turn, and increasing by one box of damage each additional turn. Resolve the damage at the end of each Combat Turn by making a Damage Resistance Test using the victim's Body + half Impact armor. Ammo or explosives carried by a victim may go off. The gamemaster should reduce the Force of the fire accordingly for extinguishing efforts.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Influence (Mental)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: P &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell implants a single suggestion in the victim's mind, like a powerful post-hypnotic command. The subject will carry out this suggestion as if it were her own idea and it will then fade. If confronted with the wrongness of the suggestion, the subject can make a Willpower Test to overcome it as described under Mental Manipulations, p. 210. The caster can also withdraw the suggestion at any time.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Levitate (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Levitate allows the caster to telekinetically lift a person or object and move it around. The caster must achieve a threshold on the Spellcasting Test equal to 1 per 200 kg of the subject's mass. The subject of the spell can be moved anywhere in the caster's line of sight at a Movement rate equal to the spell's Force x net Spellcasting hits in meters per turn. Objects flung into other things should be handled as a Ranged Attack Test (see Fling), inflicting a number of boxes of Stun damage as decided by the gamemaster (especially sharp or dangerous objects may do Physical damage at the gamemaster's discretion). If the caster is attempting to levitate an item held by a living being, make an Opposed Test between the spell's Force x 2 and the holder's Strength + Body. The caster must have at least 1 net hit to levitate the item away. If the caster is attempting to levitate an unwilling living being, the Opposed Test uses the target's Strength + Body. You can use this spell to levitate yourself, if desired.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Light (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) - 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			This spell creates a mobile point of light, illuminating a radius around it equal to the spell's Force in meters. The spell cannot be used to blind, but does offset darkness visibility modifiers. Each hit on the Spellcasting Test counters a -1 die penalty for visibility.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Magic Fingers (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Magic Fingers creates a psychokinetic effect like "invisible hands" that can hold or manipulate items. The hits on the Spellcasting + Magic Test become the spell's effective Strength and Agility. The caster can use skills remotely with Magic Fingers, but all tests receive a -2 dice pool modifier due to problems of fine control. Even simple actions like picking up a coin may require an Agility Test, at the gamemaster's discretion. The caster can fight, pick a lock, or perform any other action, using the magic fingers as if they were real hands. The spell can reach any point the caster can see, and Clairvoyance or remote-viewing technology can be used to get a close-up of the scene as long as it is within the caster's normal line of sight. This spell comes in very handy for disarming bombs and handling other hazardous work from a safe distance.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Mana Barrier (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: M &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Mana Barrier creates an invisible barrier of magical energy with a Force equal to the net hits scored. This barrier does not restrict living beings or physical objects, but it does impede spirits, foci, dual beings, and spells. If cast on the astral plane, it also impedes astral forms and restricts visibility. Any target of a spell that is on the other side of the Mana Barrier receives a bonus to its spell resistance dice pool equal to the barrier's Force. If the target had no resistance dice pool, but instead has an Object Resistance threshold, increase the threshold by 1 for every increment of 3 Force in the Mana Barrier (round up). See p. 194 for more information on mana barriers.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Petrify (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Petrify transforms living tissue into stone-like calcium carbonate. The caster must win an Opposed Test pitting her Spellcasting + Magic against the target's Body (+ Counterspelling). Additionally, the spell's Force must equal or exceed the target's Body. Non-living material- including clothing, gear, and cyberware-is not affected. The target is not conscious while under the effects of this spell, and any damage suffered by the stone-like form affects the target normally. While petrified, the subject has a barrier Armor rating equal to Body + net hits (see Barriers, p. 194).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Physical Barrier (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Barrier spells create glowing, translucent force-fields with both 1 point of Armor and Structure rating per hit (see Barriers, p. 194). The caster can form the barrier as a dome with a radius and height equal to the spell's normal radius. The caster can also form a wall with a height and length equal to the spell's Force. The caster can adjust size of the barrier the same as the radius of an area spell (p. 183). Physical Barrier creates a physical wall. Anything the size of a molecule (or less) can pass through the barrier, including air or other gases. Anything bigger treats the barrier as a normal physical wall. Attacks directed through a barrier have a -1 dice pool visibility penalty. The barrier does not impede spells. The barrier can be brought down by physical attacks, but as long as it is sustained it regenerates damage quickly-any reductions in Structure Rating are restored at the beginning of the next Combat Turn. If the barrier is penetrated, however, it collapses and the spell ends. Physical Barrier cannot be used on the astral plane.
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Poltergeist (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 3
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Poltergeist picks up all small objects (up to a kilogram in mass) within the spell's area and whirls them around in random patterns. This imposes a -2 dice pool visibility penalty in the area. The spell inflicts 2 boxes of Stun damage (resisted with Reaction + Impact armor) to anyone in the area each Combat Turn, whacking them with flying debris. Poltergeist may do more damage in cluttered environments, or inflict Physical damage if the gamemaster feels the debris is sufficiently dangerous (broken glass and nails, for example).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Shadow (Environmental, Area)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS (A) &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Shadow creates a globe of darkness with a radius equal to the spell's Force in meters. Every hit imposes a -1 die pool visibility modifier against targets within the area (maximum -6).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Shapechange (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Shapechange transforms a voluntary subject into a normal (non-paranormal) critter, though the subject retains human consciousness. The subject can only assume the form of a critter whose base Body rating is 2 points greater or less than her own. Consult the Critters section, p. 292, for the subject's Physical attributes while in critter form. Add 1 to the critter's Base attribute Ratings for every hit the caster generates. Her Mental attributes remain unchanged. This spell does not transform clothing and equipment. Magicians in critter form can still cast spells, but cannot perform other tasks requiring speech. Critter form works like the Shapechange spell, but only allows the subject to change into a specific non-paranormal animal. Each critter form is a different spell (Eagle Form, Wolf Form, and so on).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="(Critter) Form (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 1
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Shapechange transforms a voluntary subject into a normal (non-paranormal) critter, though the subject retains human consciousness. The subject can only assume the form of a critter whose base Body rating is 2 points greater or less than her own. Consult the Critters section, p. 292, for the subject's Physical attributes while in critter form. Add 1 to the critter's Base attribute Ratings for every hit the caster generates. Her Mental attributes remain unchanged. This spell does not transform clothing and equipment. Magicians in critter form can still cast spells, but cannot perform other tasks requiring speech. Critter form works like the Shapechange spell, but only allows the subject to change into a specific non-paranormal animal. Each critter form is a different spell (Eagle Form, Wolf Form, and so on).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
	<Spell name="Turn to Goo (Physical)" type="Manipulation">
		<Stats>
			Type: P &#8226; Range: LOS &#8226; Duration: S &#8226; DV: (F &#247; 2) + 2
		</Stats>
		<Desc>
			Turn to Goo transforms living tissue into a sticky, glue-like substance. The caster must win an Opposed Test pitting her Spellcasting + Magic against the target's Body (+ Counterspelling). Additionally, the spell's Force must equal or exceed the target's Body. Non-living material- including clothing, gear, and cyberware-is not affected. The target is not conscious while under the effects of this spell, and any damage suffered by the gooey form affects the target normally. The goo has a barrier Armor rating equal to Body + net hits (see Barriers, p. 194).
		</Desc>
	</Spell>
<!-- End Spells -->
<!-- Start Sprites -->
	<Sprite name="Courier Sprite">
		<Stats>
			Pilot: R Response: R + 1 Firewall: R + 1 Matrix INIT: R x 3 IP: 3 Edge: R Res: R
		</Stats>
		<Skills>
			Computer, Data Search, Hacking
		</Skills>
		<ComplexForms>
			Analyze, Edit, Encrypt, Stealth, Track
		</ComplexForms>
		<Powers>
			Cookie, Hash
		</Powers>
		<OptionalCFs>
			Browse, Command, Decrypt, Exploit, Scan
		</OptionalCFs>
		<Desc>
			These sprites are messengers and trackers, good for securely conveying important data through the Matrix.
		</Desc>
	</Sprite>
	<Sprite name="Crack Sprite">
		<Stats>
			Pilot: R Response: R + 1 Firewall: R  Matrix INIT: R x 3 IP: 3 Edge: R Res: R
		</Stats>
		<Skills>
			Computer, Electronic Warfare, Hacking
		</Skills>
		<ComplexForms>
			Analyze, Exploit, Stealth
		</ComplexForms>
		<Powers>
			Suppression
		</Powers>
		<OptionalCFs>
			Decrypt, Defuse, Edit, Scan, Spoof
		</OptionalCFs>
		<Desc>
			Crack sprites are masters at finding programming flaws and exploits. They are useful as hacking aids.
		</Desc>
	</Sprite>
	<Sprite name="Data Sprite">
		<Stats>
			Pilot: R Response: R Firewall: R - 2  Matrix INIT: R x 2 IP: 3 Edge: R Res: R
		</Stats>
		<Skills>
			Computer, Data Search, Electronic Warfare
		</Skills>
		<ComplexForms>
			Analyze, Browse, Edit, Decrypt
		</ComplexForms>
		<Powers>
			Steganography, Watermark
		</Powers>
		<OptionalCFs>
			Defuse, Encrypt, Sniffer, Stealth, any linguasoft (p. 330)
		</OptionalCFs>
		<Desc>
			Data sprites excel at finding and manipulating information. They make excellent searchbots and librarians.
		</Desc>
	</Sprite>
	<Sprite name="Fault Sprite">
		<Stats>
			Pilot: R Response: R + 2 Firewall: R + 1  Matrix INIT: R x 3 IP: 3 Edge: R Res: R
		</Stats>
		<Skills>
			Computer, Cybercombat, Hacking
		</Skills>
		<ComplexForms>
			Analyze, Armor, Attack, Stealth
		</ComplexForms>
		<Powers>
			Electron Storm
		</Powers>
		<OptionalCFs>
			Black Hammer, Blackout, Exploit, Medic
		</OptionalCFs>
		<Desc>
			Fault sprites are designed to inject code errors and cause programs to fail.
		</Desc>
	</Sprite>
	<Sprite name="Machine Sprite">
		<Stats>
			Pilot: R Response: R Firewall: R + 2  Matrix INIT: R x 2 IP: 3 Edge: R Res: R
		</Stats>
		<Skills>
			Computer, Electronic Warfare, Hardware
		</Skills>
		<ComplexForms>
			Analyze, Command
		</ComplexForms>
		<Powers>
			Diagnostics, Gremlins, Stability
		</Powers>
		<OptionalCFs>
			Decrypt, Edit, Medic, any autosoft (p. 246)
		</OptionalCFs>
		<Desc>
			Machine sprites are adept at manipulating devices. Of all sprites, they are the most likely to actually interact with the physical world via a device.
		</Desc>
	</Sprite>
<!-- End Sprites -->
<!-- Start Weapons -->
	<WeaponCategory name="Melee Weapons">
		<Weapon name="Combat Axe" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: 2 Damage: (STR/2 + 4)P AP: -1 Availability: 8R </Stats>
			<Cost>600</Cost>
			<Desc>This two-handed tungsten alloy axe typically comes with a spring-loaded thrusting point concealed in the handle.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Forearm Snap-Blades" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: - Damage: (STR/2 + 2)P AP: - Availability: 6R </Stats>
			<Cost>150</Cost>
			<Desc>These external spurs feature a forearm sheath with three blades that extend and retract via muscle-movement commands or wireless link.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Katana" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: (STR/2 + 3)P AP: -1 Availability: 4R </Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>The legendary, two-handed sword of the samurai-chop up your enemies with style.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Knife" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: - Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: - Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>20</Cost>
			<Desc>A basic, all-purpose cutting tool.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Monofilament Sword" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: (STR/2 + 3)P AP: -1 Availability: 8R </Stats>
			<Cost>750</Cost>
			<Desc>This well-balanced broadsword features superfine monofilament wire attached to its edges.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Survival Knife" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: - Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: -1 Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>This fine quality blade features several accessories: retractable GPS monitor, micro-lighter, and a compartment in the handle that will hold one small item. The flat sides of the blade are covered with a non-toxic chemical that can be activated to provide 2 hours of phosphorescent light.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Sword" type="Blade">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: (STR/2 + 3)P AP: - Availability: 4R </Stats>
			<Cost>350</Cost>
			<Desc>Get medieval with this sharp and heavy toy of destruction. Swords encompass a variety of one-handed blades, from scimitars to machetes to longswords.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Club" type="Club">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: - Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>30</Cost>
			<Desc>Anything from a hickory "tire-knocker" to a baseball bat to a two-by-four with a rusty nail.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Extendable Baton" type="Club">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: - Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>The shaft of this club telescopes out when flicked sharply. When retracted, it is more easily concealed (-2).</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Sap" type="Club">
			<Stats>Reach: - Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: - Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>30</Cost>
			<Desc>A small, springy club, specially designed for concealability (-2).</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Staff" type="Club">
			<Stats>Reach: 2 Damage: (STR/2 + 2)P AP: - Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>A large, heavy stick, popular with some magicians for that traditional look.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Stun Baton" type="Club">
			<Stats>Reach: 1 Damage: 6S(e) AP: -half Availability: 4T </Stats>
			<Cost>400</Cost>
			<Desc>The standard riot-control weapon, this weighted stick delivers an electrical charge that deals Electricity damage (p. 163). It has 10 charges; when plugged in, it recharges at a rate of one charge per 10 seconds.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Monofilament Whip" type="Exotic Weapon">
			<Stats>Reach: 2 Damage: 8P AP: -4 Availability: 12F </Stats>
			<Cost>3000</Cost>
			<Desc>One of the deadliest weapons on the streets, this nanowire whip cuts through bone and armor with horrifying ease. The line extends out to two meters, and retracts into the weapon's haft when not in use. The whip action, the presence of a weighted tip, and the danger of the monofilament line make wielding this weapon difficult at best. If an attacker using a monofilament whip rolls a glitch, she has either tangled the line around itself, gotten the weighted tip stuck on something, or inadvertently cut something nearby apart. If the attacker rolls a critical glitch, she has struck herself and must resist the whip's standard Damage Code.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Pole Arm" type="Exotic Weapon">
			<Stats>Reach: 2 Damage: (STR/2 + 2)P AP: -2 Availability: 4R </Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>This spear-like weapon usually features an axe-head or similar blade and has become quite popular with trolls and other large individuals, even though it's not easy to handle.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Shock Glove" type="Unarmed Combat">
			<Stats>Reach: - Damage: 5S(e) AP: -half Availability: 3R </Stats>
			<Cost>200</Cost>
			<Desc>This pair of insulated plas-fabric gloves has a wire mesh that discharges electric current when triggered by impact. The gloves deal Electricity damage (p. 163) and have 10 charges (each); when plugged in, they recharge at a rate of one charge per 10 seconds.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
	</WeaponCategory>
	<WeaponCategory name="Projectile and Throwing Weapons">
		<Weapon name="Bow" type="Bow">
			<Stats>Damage: (STR Min + 2)P AP: - Availability: Rating x 2 Cost: Rating x 100</Stats>
			<Cost>100</Cost>
			<Desc>A traditional longbow of fiberglass or wood, or a modern compound-and-pulley bow. Reloading the bow takes one "Ready Weapon" Action (p. 147).</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Arrow" type="Bow">
			<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Availability: Rating x 2 Cost: Rating x 5</Stats>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Desc>A basic arrow for use in a bow.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Injection Arrow" type="Bow">
			<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Availability: 8R </Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>An injection arrow causes the same damage as a regular arrow/bolt, but an attack that inflicts at least 1 point of damage will also deliver one dose of whatever chemical substance the arrow/bolt was loaded with. This counts as an injection attack vector (p. 254).</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Light Crossbow" type="Crossbow">
			<Stats>Damage: 3P AP: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
			<Cost>300</Cost>
			<Desc>Modern crossbows are equipped with automatic reloading devices to allow for faster firing rates (reloading doesn't require a Ready Weapon action, unless you happen to be using a museum piece). Crossbows also feature internal magazines (m) holding up to 4 bolts. Available in Light, Medium, and Heavy sizes.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Medium Crossbow" type="Crossbow">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Availability: 4R </Stats>
			<Cost>500</Cost>
			<Desc>Modern crossbows are equipped with automatic reloading devices to allow for faster firing rates (reloading doesn't require a Ready Weapon action, unless you happen to be using a museum piece). Crossbows also feature internal magazines (m) holding up to 4 bolts. Available in Light, Medium, and Heavy sizes.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Heavy Crossbow" type="Crossbow">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -1 Availability: 8R </Stats>
			<Cost>750</Cost>
			<Desc>Modern crossbows are equipped with automatic reloading devices to allow for faster firing rates (reloading doesn't require a Ready Weapon action, unless you happen to be using a museum piece). Crossbows also feature internal magazines (m) holding up to 4 bolts. Available in Light, Medium, and Heavy sizes.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Bolt" type="Crossbow">
			<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Desc>A basic bolt for use in a crossbow.</Desc>
		</Weapon>	
		<Weapon name="Injection Bolt" type="Crossbow">
			<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Availability: 8R </Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>An injection bolt causes the same damage as a regular arrow/bolt, but an attack that inflicts at least 1 point of damage will also deliver one dose of whatever chemical substance the arrow/bolt was loaded with. This counts as an injection attack vector (p. 254).</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Shuriken" type="Throwing Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: (STR/2)P AP: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
			<Cost>30</Cost>
			<Desc>This multi-edged airfoil throwing blade is available in many different styles. A character can ready Agility &#247; 2 shuriken per Ready Weapon action.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Throwing Knife" type="Throwing Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: (STR/2 + 1)P AP: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
			<Cost>20</Cost>
			<Desc>Any of a variety of slim knives or spikes. A character can ready Agility &#247; 2 throwing knives per Ready Weapon action.</Desc>
		</Weapon>
	</WeaponCategory>
	<WeaponCategory name="Firearms">
		<Weapon name="Defiance EX Shocker" type="Tasers">
			<Stats>Damage: 8S(e) AP: -half Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 4(m) Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>150</Cost>
			<Desc>The EX Shocker fires up to 4 darts that trail wires of up to 20 meters long. It also features contacts that allow it to be used as stun weapon in melee.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Yamaha Pulsar" type="Tasers">
			<Stats>Damage: 6S(e) AP: -half Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 4(m) Availability: - </Stats>
			<Cost>150</Cost>
			<Desc>The Pulsar fires capacitor darts at a target, eliminating the wires that trail from dart to weapon with other taser models.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Raecor Sting" type="Holdouts">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P(f) AP: +5 Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 5(c) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>350</Cost>
			<Desc>This weapon's "lemon-squeezer" design (the gun's barrel protrudes from between the firer's fingers and it's fired by making a fist) and its polyresin composition (undetectable by MAD scanners) makes for a very stealthy weapon. It fires flechette ammunition only (already included in the weapon stats).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Raecor Sting" type="Holdouts">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 6(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>100</Cost>
			<Desc>This small, lightweight weapon is made of composite materials (MADs suffer a -2 dice pool modifier to detect it, see p. 262). It is a common weapon among those on society's bottom rung.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Colt America L36" type="Light Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 11(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>150</Cost>
			<Desc>An old-timer with a very good reputation, this sleek automatic pistol is easy to conceal and commonly available.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Fichetti Security 600" type="Light Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>450</Cost>
			<Desc>Designed as a light sidearm for security personnel, this pistol has a highly efficient feeding mechanism that allows it to hold an incredible 30 bullets. It comes fully equipped with a detachable folding stock and laser sight.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Hammerli 620S" type="Light Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA RC: 1 Ammo: 6(c) Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>650</Cost>
			<Desc>Sleek and stylish, the Hammerli offers the range of a heavy pistol within a light pistol casing (use Heavy Pistol ranges, p. 151). It also includes integral gas-vent and smartgun systems.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Yamaha Saukra Fubuki" type="Light Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA/BF RC: (1) Ammo: 10(ml) x 4 Availability: 10R</Stats>
			<Cost>2000</Cost>
			<Desc>The "Cherry-Blossom Storm" is the flagship for Yamaha's new line of electronic weapons that feature no moving parts. Rather than a standard magazine, the bullets are stacked in-line in each of the four barrels, allowing the firing of ultra-fast short bursts. The Fubuki may only fire narrow bursts (not wide), but burst recoil is handled like SA recoil (-1 Recoil on the second burst each Action Phase only). Includes an integral folding stock.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares Predator IV" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: -1 Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 15(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>350</Cost>
			<Desc>The all-time favorite sidearm among mercenaries and security services. Includes a smartgun system.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares Viper Silvergun" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 8P(f) AP: +5 Mode: SA/BF RC: - Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 5R</Stats>
			<Cost>50</Cost>
			<Desc>The Slivergun is a sleek weapon with burst fire capabilities and built-in sound suppression. It fires metal slivers that count as flechette ammunition (already factored in to the Damage Code).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Colt Manhunter" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: -1 Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 16(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>300</Cost>
			<Desc>Popular among law enforcement, the Manhunter features a built-in laser sight.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Remington Roomsweeper" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: -1 Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>250</Cost>
			<Desc>This short-barreled "shotgun pistol" can be loaded with shot rounds rather than slugs, in which cases it uses heavy-pistol ranges but shotgun rules (Shotguns, pp. 154-155).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Remington Roomsweeper w/ Flechettes" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P(f) AP: +5 Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>250</Cost>
			<Desc>This short-barreled "shotgun pistol" can be loaded with shot rounds rather than slugs, in which cases it uses heavy-pistol ranges but shotgun rules (Shotguns, pp. 154-155).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ruger Super Warhawk" type="Heavy Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -2 Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 6(cy) Availability: 3R</Stats>
			<Cost>250</Cost>
			<Desc>Feeling lucky, punk? This heavy revolver looks as scary as the holes it tears through things. It cannot be equipped with a silencer.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ceska Black Scorpion" type="Machine Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA/BF RC: (1) Ammo: 35(c) Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>550</Cost>
			<Desc>This classic machine pistol combines concealability with burst fire capabilities. It comes equipped with an integral folding stock.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Steyr TMP" type="Machine Pistol">
			<Stats>Damage: 4P AP: - Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: - Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>600</Cost>
			<Desc>This lightweight polymer-frame pistol is capable of full autofire, but its lack of recoil compensation makes it difficult to control.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="AK-97 Carbine" type="Submachine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: (1) Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>400</Cost>
			<Desc>The AK-97 has earned its fame in many campaignsaround the globe. Its reliability is legendary-you can bury it for 10 years, dig it up, and fire it immediately without a single problem. Includes a detachable folding stock.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK-227-X" type="Submachine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: (1) Ammo: 28(c) Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>800</Cost>
			<Desc>The SMG of choice for many corporate and military security forces. The HK 227-X boasts a retractable stock, smartgun system, and integral sound suppressor.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK MP-5 TX" type="Submachine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: 2(3) Ammo: 20(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>550</Cost>
			<Desc>Carrying on the classic MP-5 design, an aggressive marketing campaign and featured usage on the blockbuster Combat Mage: TNG sim have made it popular on the streets. The TX includes a gas-vent 2 system, a l laser sight, and a detachable folding stock.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Imgram Smartgun X" type="Submachine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: BF/FA RC: 2(3) Ammo: 32(c) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>650</Cost>
			<Desc>This smartgun upgrade features gas-vent 2, a smartgun system, a sound suppressor, and a detachable folding stock.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Uzi IV" type="Submachine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: BF RC: (1) Ammo: 24(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>500</Cost>
			<Desc>A worthy descendent of the famous Israeli weapon, this SMG features an integral folding stock and laser sight.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="AK-97" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: - Ammo: 38(c) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>500</Cost>
			<Desc>The common version of this premier assault rifle, ideal for anyone with a small budget.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares Alpha" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: 2 Ammo: 42(c) Availability: 12F</Stats>
			<Cost>1700</Cost>
			<Desc>Designed for Ares Firewatch special forces, the Alpha includes an underbarrel grenade launcher, a smartgun system, and a special chamber design that provides 2 points of recoil compensation. Comes with the "Ares Alpha Grenade Launcher".
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares Alpha Grenade Launcher" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: Grenade AP: - Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 6(c) Availability: 12F</Stats>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Desc>Designed for Ares Firewatch special forces, the Alpha includes an underbarrel grenade launcher, a smartgun system, and a special chamber design that provides 2 points of recoil compensation. Comes with the "Ares Alpha".
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="FN HAR" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: 2 Ammo: 35(c) Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>This assault rifle is increasingly popular with corporate response teams and private security forces specializing in high-threat areas. It comes with a laser sight and a Rating 2 gas-vent recoil compensation system.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: (1) Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>2500</Cost>
			<Desc>This award-winning modular "weapons platform" can turn a single soldier into a one-man army. The baseline assault rifle features lightweight composite construction, a smartgun system, rigid stock with shock pad, and an underbarrel grenade launcher with grenade link. The weapon may be reassembled with optional modules- taking an Automatics + Agility (5, 1 minute) Extended Test to swap them in-into either an underbarrel shotgun, compact carbine, sniper rifle (with an imaging scope), or LMG (with bipod) configuration. Comes with the HK XM30 Grenade Launcher.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30 Grenade Launcher" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: Grenade AP: - Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 8(c) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Desc>The underbarrel grenade launcher with grenade link on the HK XM30. Comes with the HK XM30.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30 Shotgun" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: +1 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 10(c) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>An additional module that replaces the XM30 underbarrel grenade launcher with a shotgun.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30 Carbine" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 5P AP: - Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: (1) Ammo: 30(c) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>500</Cost>
			<Desc>An additional module that replaces the XM30 main barrel with a compact carbine.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30 Sniper" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -2 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 10(c) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>An additional module that replaces the XM30 main barrel with a semi-automatic sniper rifle (with an imaging scope).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="HK XM30 LMG" type="Assault Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: BF/FA RC: 2(3) Ammo: 100(belt) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>An additional module that replaces the XM30 main barrel with a light machine gun (with bipod).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ruger 100" type="Sport Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -1 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 5(m) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>900</Cost>
			<Desc>This sport rifle is the favorite weapon for many professional hunters. It features a built-in imaging scope and a rigid stock with shock pad.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="PJSS Elephant Rifle" type="Sport Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 9P AP: -1 Mode: SS RC: (1) Ammo: 2(b) Availability: 12R</Stats>
			<Cost>6000</Cost>
			<Desc>If you want to shoot something big from a safe distance, this huge double-barreled rifle is your weapon of choice. Its two barrels can be shot at once with +1 DV and a -1 Recoil modifier. Includes a rigid stock with shock pad.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ranger Arms SM-4" type="Sniper Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 8P AP: -3 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 15(c) Availability: 16F</Stats>
			<Cost>6200</Cost>
			<Desc>This rifle features a silencer, an imaging scope, and a rigid stock with shock pad. The SM-4 disassembles completely in order to fit into a standard briefcase; assembling or disassembling it takes 3 Complex Actions.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Walter MA-2100" type="Sniper Rifle">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -3 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 10(m) Availability: 10F</Stats>
			<Cost>5000</Cost>
			<Desc>The chosen sniper rifle of the Confederationof American States Army, the MA-2100 is designed to military specifications. It is far more stable and hardy than other sniper rifles (dispensing with the Edge Test when used in Ranged Combat outside its sniping role, though not Melee Combat). However, the downside to this model is that it cannot be disassembled to fit into a briefcase. It comes with an internal smartgun system and a rigid stock with shock pad.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Mossberg AM-CMDT" type="Shotgun">
			<Stats>Damage: 9P(f) AP: +5 Mode: SA/BF/FA RC: - Ammo: 10(c) Availability: 12R</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>This heavy automatic shotgun can fill a whole room with whirling pellets of shot in an instant, which makes it a terrifying weapon in house-to-house combat. It fires flechette ammuniton only (already included in the weapon stats).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Remington 990" type="Shotgun">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -1 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>550</Cost>
			<Desc>The Remington includes an imaging scope and a rigid stock with shock pad. It can fire regular slug or flechette ammunition.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Remington 990 w/ Flechettes" type="Shotgun">
			<Stats>Damage: 9P(f) AP: +5 Mode: SA RC: (1) Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 4R</Stats>
			<Cost>550</Cost>
			<Desc>The Remington includes an imaging scope and a rigid stock with shock pad. It can fire regular slug or flechette ammunition.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares S-III Super Squirt" type="Special Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: Chemical AP: - Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 20(c) Availability: 4</Stats>
			<Cost>500</Cost>
			<Desc>This popular non-lethal weapon fires dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, a carrier that forces the skin to absorb chemicals) gel packs that can deliver a chemical substance over light pistol ranges. The attack itself causes no damage, but when the target is hit successfully, the DMSO delivers the substance directly into the target's bloodstream (Using Toxic Substances, p. 254).
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Fichetti Pain Inducer" type="Special Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: Special AP: -half Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: Special Availability: 8R</Stats>
			<Cost>2000</Cost>
			<Desc>This non-lethal weapon uses a microwave beam that excites the molecules of the target's skin, inflicting intense pain (the target feels as if she were on fire). Treat this like a toxin attack (p. 254) with a Power of 8. The target resists with Body + half impact armor (round up). If the modified Power exceeds the target's Willpower, the target must spend her next Action Phase doing whatever it takes to get away from the pain (usually this means running away). The attacker can continue to hold her beam on a target with a Complex Action unless the gamemaster deems the target has dodged away or found cover. If the target cannot flee, she is incapacitated with pain and suffers a dice pool modifier equal to the modified Power on all tests for as long as the beam is trained on her. The Pain Inducer has 10 charges; when attached to a power point, it reloads one charge per 10 seconds.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Parashield Dart Pistol" type="Special Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: As Drug/Toxin AP: -2 Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 5(c) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>600</Cost>
			<Desc>The industry standard dart pistol, the Parashield dart pistol fires injection darts ( Injection Darts, p. 324) with narcoject or another payload. The Parashield dart pistol uses heavy pistol ranges.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Parashield Dart Rifle" type="Special Weapons">
			<Stats>Damage: As Drug/Toxin AP: -2 Mode: SA RC: 0 Ammo: 10(c) Availability: 6R</Stats>
			<Cost>1700</Cost>
			<Desc>The rifle version of the Parashield Dart Pistol, this rifle uses compressed air to fire injection darts. The Parashield rifle uses sporting rifle ranges.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ingram White Knight" type="Light Machine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 6P AP: -1 Mode: BF/FA RC: 5(6) Ammo: 50(c) or 100(belt) Availability: 12F</Stats>
			<Cost>2000</Cost>
			<Desc>When you're looking for a good bang for your buck, the White Knight is your kind of gun. It's equipped with a detachable folding stock and an integral gas-vent system that provides 5 points of recoil compensation and cannot be further upgraded.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Stoner-Ares M202" type="Medium Machine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 7P AP: -2 Mode: FA RC: - Ammo: 50(c) or 100(belt) Availability: 12F</Stats>
			<Cost>4500</Cost>
			<Desc>This MMG packs a tremendous punch into a relatively light framework made of extra-durable compounds. Due to its comparatively smaller size, it's a very popular secondary weapon for military vehicles, but can also be equipped with various accessories to make it into a personal weapon.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ultimax HMG-2" type="Heavy Machine Gun">
			<Stats>Damage: 20P AP: -5 Mode: FA RC: 3(10) Ammo: 50(c) or 100(belt) Availability: 15F</Stats>
			<Cost>7500</Cost>
			<Desc>Equipped with a detachable tripod, a rigid stock with shock pad, and a gas-vent 3 system, the Ultimax is usually fired from a prone, sitting, or kneeling position, though some trolls might be strong enough to fire it while standing.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Panther XXL" type="Assault Cannon">
			<Stats>Damage: 10P AP: -5 Mode: SS RC: (1) Ammo: 15(c) Availability: 20F</Stats>
			<Cost>5500</Cost>
			<Desc>This enormous assault cannon fires special ammunition common to the primary weapon in many small tanks. It comes with a smartgun system.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Ares Antioch-2" type="Grenade Launcher">
			<Stats>Damage: Grenade AP: - Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 8F</Stats>
			<Cost>600</Cost>
			<Desc>The Antioch-2 features a classic grenade launcher design, combined with a smartgun system.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="ArmTech MGL-12" type="Grenade Launcher">
			<Stats>Damage: Grenade AP: - Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 12(c) Availability: 10F</Stats>
			<Cost>2000</Cost>
			<Desc>This bullpup-configuration model is popular, since it fires in semi-auto mode and carries more minigrenades than its competitors.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Aztechnology Striker" type="Missile Launcher">
			<Stats>Damage: Missile AP: - Mode: SS RC: - Ammo: 1(ml) Availability: 10F</Stats>
			<Cost>1000</Cost>
			<Desc>The Striker is an extremely light disposable launcher-perfect for shadowrunners who want to deliver a punch and make a quick, unencumbered getaway.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
		<Weapon name="Mitsubishi Yakusoku MRL" type="Missile Launcher">
			<Stats>Damage: Missile AP: - Mode: SA RC: - Ammo: 8(m) Availability: 20F</Stats>
			<Cost>12000</Cost>
			<Desc>The internal loading mechanism of the Yakusoku Multi Rocket Launcher allows it to insert up to 4 different types of missiles (2 each) and choose freely (via the integrated smartgun connection) which of them to fire with each shooting action. Its two firing tubes also allow for a quicker rate of fire.
			</Desc>
		</Weapon>
	</WeaponCategory>
<!-- End Weapons -->
<!-- Start WeaponAccessories -->
	<WeaponAccessory name="Airburst Link">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 6R </Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>This grenade/rocket launcher smartgun accessory uses the distance to the target as determined by the rangefinder and programs the minigrenade/rocket to explode in the air after it has traveled the target distance. This airburst setting reduces the scatter from 3D6 or 4D6 to 2D6. All minigrenades/rockets can be timed in this manner. Air-timed airburst attacks explode in the Action Phase in which they were launched.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Bipod">
		<Stats>Mount: Under Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>Bipods are two-legged braces that extend downward from the weapon, allowing it to be fired low to the ground with the user in a sitting or prone position. A bipod can be attached to the underbarrel mount and provides 2 points of recoil compensation when properly deployed. Attaching or removing it takes a Complex Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Concealable Holster">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>75</Cost>
		<Desc>Various types of holsters can be worn over the hip, in the small of the back, under the arm, on the forearm, or on the ankle. The concealable holster adds -1 to the item's Concealability (p. 311).</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Gas-Vent 2 System">
		<Stats>Mount: Barrel Availability: 4R </Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>Gas-vent recoil compensation systems vent a weapon's barrel gases at a specific vector to counter barrel climb. Gasvent systems can be built into machine pistols, SMGs, assault rifles, and machine guns. Installing them takes up the barrel mount and requires an Armorer + Logic (8, 1 hour) Extended Test; once installed, they cannot be removed. Weapons already equipped with a built-in gas-vent system cannot be equipped with an additional gas-vent system. The gas-vent 2 system provides 2 points of recoil compensation. the gas-vent 3 system provides 3 points of recoil compensation.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Gas-Vent 3 System">
		<Stats>Mount: Barrel Availability: 6R </Stats>
		<Cost>400</Cost>
		<Desc>Gas-vent recoil compensation systems vent a weapon's barrel gases at a specific vector to counter barrel climb. Gasvent systems can be built into machine pistols, SMGs, assault rifles, and machine guns. Installing them takes up the barrel mount and requires an Armorer + Logic (8, 1 hour) Extended Test; once installed, they cannot be removed. Weapons already equipped with a built-in gas-vent system cannot be equipped with an additional gas-vent system. The gas-vent 3 system provides 3 points of recoil compensation.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Gyro Stabilization">
		<Stats>Mount: Under Availability: 7 </Stats>
		<Cost>3000</Cost>
		<Desc>This is a heavy upper-body harness with an attached, articulated, gyro-stabilized arm that mounts a rifle or heavy weapon. The system neutralizes up to 6 points of recoil and movement modifiers. Attaching or removing a weapon takes a Simple Action. Getting into the gyro-mount takes 5 minutes, while using the built-in quick release to get out of it takes a Complex Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Hidden Gun Arm Slide">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>350</Cost>
		<Desc>Attached to the forearm and worn under clothing, this slide can accommodate a pistol-sized weapon. With a wireless signal or correct sequence of arm movements, the slide releases the weapon/object right into the wearer's hand. This takes only a Free Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Imaging Scope">
		<Stats>Mount: Top Availability: 3 </Stats>
		<Cost>300</Cost>
		<Desc>These classic scopes are attached to the top mount; attaching or removing them takes only a Simple Action. Imaging scopes can be upgraded with any of the vision enhancements noted on p. 333.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Laser Sight">
		<Stats>Mount: Top/Under Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>This device uses a laser beam to project a glowing red spot on the target. This provides a +1 dice pool modifier for ranged attacks (this modifier is not cumulative with smartlink bonuses). The laser sight can be attached to either the underbarrel mount or top mount. Attaching or removing it takes a Complex Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Periscope">
		<Stats>Mount: Top Availability: 3 </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>This adjustable "off-axis viewer" attaches to a topmount and allows you to target a weapon around corners.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Quick-Draw Holster">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>This easy-access holster reduces the threshold for quick drawing the holstered weapon to 2 (Quick Draw, p. 147).</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Shock Pad">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>This shock-absorbing pad can be mounted on the rigid shoulder stock of a rifle, shotgun, or heavy weapon, and provides 1 point of recoil compensation.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Silencer">
		<Stats>Mount: Barrel Availability: 8F </Stats>
		<Cost>350</Cost>
		<Desc>The silencer is a barrel-mounted accessory that reduces the sound and flash of a weapon's discharge. A silencer can only be used with single-shot or semi-automatic weapons (and not with revolvers). It applies a -4 dice pool modifier on all Perception Tests to notice the weapon's use or locate the weapon's firer. Attaching or removing a silencer takes a Complex Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Smart Firing Platform">
		<Stats>Mount: Under Availability: 12F </Stats>
		<Cost>2000</Cost>
		<Desc>This is a non-mobile robotic tripod (p. 323) equipped with a remote-control pivot that allows for a 180-degree firing arc (and a 60-degree inclination). A smartgun-equipped weapon mounted to the platform can be fired remotely or by the platform's Pilot. The platform is equipped with Pilot 3, Sensor 3, and one Targeting autosoft (p. 246) at Rating 3.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Smartgun System (external)">
		<Stats>Mount: Top/Under Availability: 4R </Stats>
		<Cost>400</Cost>
		<Desc>The smartgun system connects a firearm or projectile weapon directly to a user's smartlink (p. 333). It incorporates a laser rangefinder and a small camera, and keeps track of ammunition, heat buildup, and material stress. It allows a smartlinked character to mentally switch between gun modes, eject clips, and fire the gun without pulling the trigger. The camera allows for targeted shooting around corners, without exposing oneself to return fire. The system makes use of advanced calculation software, allowing the user to aim even weapons with a highly ballistic firing arc (like grenades) with tremendous precision over any distance. The smartgun system can also be accessed via wireless link, allowing for the gun to be remotely fired or to block the trigger (in case an opponent gets ahold of it). When used with a smartlink, it provides a +2 dice pool bonus on the ranged attack test. Retrofitting a firearm with an internal Smartgun system doubles the weapon's price. An external smartgun system can be attached to the top mount or underbarrel mount with an Armorer + Logic (4, 1 hour) Extended Test. The small camera can be equipped with vision enhancements (p. 333).</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Sound Suppressor">
		<Stats>Mount: Barrel Availability: 12F </Stats>
		<Cost>300</Cost>
		<Desc>The sound suppressor is a barrel-mounted accessory similar to the silencer but specifically designed for burst-fire and full-auto weapons. It applies a -4 dice pool modifier to Perception Tests to notice the weapon's use or locate the weapon's firer. Attaching or removing it takes a Complex Action. It must be replaced after every 300 rounds of burst or autofire.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Spare Clips">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>5</Cost>
		<Desc>Extra ammunition clips come unloaded; they can hold the maximum rounds for the weapon and are not interchangeable from weapon to weapon even within the same class.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Speed Loader">
		<Stats>Mount: - Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>25</Cost>
		<Desc>The speed loader is a simple device that can hold a ring of bullets for fast insertion into a revolver (pistol with a cylinder). See the Reloading Firearms table, p. 324.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
	<WeaponAccessory name="Tripod">
		<Stats>Mount: Under Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>300</Cost>
		<Desc>Tripods provide a stable basis to fire a weapon low to the ground with the user in a sitting or kneeling position. A tripod can be attached to the underbarrel mount and provides 6 points of recoil compensation when properly deployed. Attaching or removing it takes one Complex Action.</Desc>
	</WeaponAccessory>
<!-- End WeaponAccessories -->
<!-- Start Ammo -->
	<Ammo name="APDS">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: - AP Modifier: -4 Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 16F</Stats>
		<Cost>70</Cost>
		<Desc>Amor-Piercing Discarding Sabot (APDS) rounds are specially designed to travel at high velocities and pierce armor. APDS reduces the effectiveness of Ballistic armor (AP -4).</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Assault Cannon">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: As Cannon AP Modifier: As Cannon Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 8F</Stats>
		<Cost>450</Cost>
		<Desc>These highly stable explosive rounds are made of HDX superplast compound.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Explosive Rounds">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: +1 AP Modifier: 0 Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 8F</Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>Explosive rounds are solid slugs designed to fragment and explode on impact. They increase the DV by 1. Explosive rounds will misfire whenever a critical glitch is rolled. When this occurs, the character firing the weapon is automatically struck by one "attack," with a Damage Code equal to the normal damage done by the weapon. The character may make a damage resistance test as normal. Any attack the affected character is making at the time misses.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="EX-Explosive Rounds">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: +1 AP Modifier: -1 Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 12F</Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>This improved model of explosive rounds adds 1 to the weapon's DV and has an AP of -1. It follows all other standard explosive rounds rules.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Flechette Rounds">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: +1 AP Modifier: +5 Armor Used: Impact Availability: 2R</Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>Tiny, tightly packed metal slivers function as the business end of a flechette round. They are devastating against unprotected targets, but not very effective against rigid armor. Flechette rounds raise the DV of weapons by +2. They also raise the effective value of Impact armor (AP +5). Flechettes are resisted with Impact armor. Guns with flechette ammo already figured into their Damage Code have an (f ) notation following the Damage Code.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Gel Rounds">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: -1(Stun) AP Modifier: +2 Armor Used: Impact Availability: 4R</Stats>
		<Cost>30</Cost>
		<Desc>These non-lethal rounds use a hard jelly-like substance and are often employed for riot control. They are usually semi-rigid slugs that flatten on impact, disbursing their kinetic energy over a larger-than-normal area. Gel rounds inflict Stun damage and are resisted with Impact armor (AP +2). Gel rounds reduce the target's Body by 2 when checking for knockdown.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Injection Darts">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: As Drug/Toxin AP Modifier: - Armor Used: Impact Availability: 4R</Stats>
		<Cost>75</Cost>
		<Desc>For use with dart guns of various types-such as the Parashield pistol and rifle-injection darts carry a single dose of adrug or toxin. Effects depend on the drug payload, but to successfully deliver the payload and penetrate armor, the attacker needs two net hits on the Ranged Combat Opposed Test.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Regular Ammo">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: - AP Modifier: - Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 2R</Stats>
		<Cost>20</Cost>
		<Desc>Standard full metal jacket rounds for all kinds of uses (mostly killing).</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Stick-n-Shock">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: 6S(e) AP Modifier: -half Armor Used: Impact Availability: 5R</Stats>
		<Cost>80</Cost>
		<Desc>This is a special adhesive projectile that sticks to the target and incorporates a battery pack that delivers short bursts of high-voltage pulses. The Stick-n-Shock replaces the weapon's Damage Value with its own.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Tracer">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: - AP Modifier: - Armor Used: Ballistic Availability: 5R</Stats>
		<Cost>75</Cost>
		<Desc>Tracer ammo burns "tracers" along the line of flight, making it easier for the shooter to home in on the target. This type of ammunition can only be used in full-auto weapons and is loaded as every third round in a clip. This is an exception to the restriction of one type of ammunition to a clip. Non-smartgun users firing tracer rounds receive a +1 dice pool modifier at all ranges beyond Short when firing a short burst, +2 when firing a long burst, and +3 when firing a full burst.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
	<Ammo name="Taser Dart">
		<Stats>Damage Modifier: As Taser AP Modifier: -half Armor Used: Impact Availability: 2</Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>These darts are designed to be loaded into taser weapons.</Desc>
	</Ammo>
<!-- End Ammo -->
<!-- Start Grenades -->
	<Grenade name="Flash-Bang">
		<Stats>Damage: 6S AP: -3 Blast: 10m Radius Availability: 6R</Stats>
		<Cost>30</Cost>
		<Desc>Upon detonation, flash-bang grenades spread a metallic powder out over the area that ignites in contact with the oxygen in the atmosphere, creating a loud, bright, shocking blast distributed equally over a radius of 10 meters.</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="Flash-Pak">
		<Stats>Damage: Special AP: - Blast: Special Availability: 4</Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>The size of a pack of cigarettes, this unit contains four quartz-halogen micro-flashes designed to fire in random strobe sequences to disorient, distract, and blind opponents. Anyone facing a flash-pak receives a -4 dice pool modifier on attack tests due to the intense glare (flare compensation reduces this modifer to -2). The flashpak has 10 charges; when activated, it uses up one charge per Combat Turn. When plugged in, it recharges one charge per 10 seconds.</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="Gragmentation">
		<Stats>Damage: 12P(f) AP: +5 Blast: -1/m Radius Availability: 10F</Stats>
		<Cost>35</Cost>
		<Desc>These are designed to spread a cloud of deadly shrapnel over a large area, seriously injuring soft targets. Their damage value reduces by -1 per meter from the point of the explosion's origin.</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="High Explosive">
		<Stats>Damage: 10P AP: -2 Blast: -2/m Radius Availability: 7F</Stats>
		<Cost>45</Cost>
		<Desc>These grenades are designed to deliver a tremendous blast, penetrating even heavily armored targets. Their damage value reduces by -2 per meter from the point of the explosion's origin.</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="Gas">
		<Stats>Damage: Chemical AP: - Blast: 10m Radius Availability: 4+Chemical</Stats>
		<Cost>20</Cost>
		<Desc>Instead of exploding, the gas grenade releases a cloud of gas over an area with a diameter of 20 meters. This is usually riot control/CS gas, but many other chemicals can be chosen (p. 255). The cloud lasts for approximately 4 Combat Turns (less in windy areas, longer in confined areas at the gamemaster's discretion).</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="Smoke">
		<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Blast: 10m Radius Availability: 4R</Stats>
		<Cost>30</Cost>
		<Desc>Similar to the gas grenade, the smoke grenade releases a cloud of smoke over an area with a diameter of 20 meters. The cloud obscures vision, applying visibility modifiers for smoke to relevant tests. It lasts for approximately 4 Combat Turns (less in windy areas, longer in confined areas at the gamemaster's discretion).</Desc>
	</Grenade>
	<Grenade name="Thermal Smoke">
		<Stats>Damage: - AP: - Blast: 10m Radius Availability: 6R</Stats>
		<Cost>35</Cost>
		<Desc>These are the same as smoke grenades, except that the smoke contains hot particles that obscure thermographic vision; apply the visibility modifiers for thermal smoke.</Desc>
	</Grenade>
<!-- End Grenades -->
<!-- Start Rockets/Missiles -->
	<RocketMissile name="Anti-Vehicle" type="Rocket">
		<Stats>Damage: 16P AP: -2/-6 Blast: -4m Radius Availability: 20F</Stats>
		<Cost>1000</Cost>
		<Desc>AV rockets/missiles contain a shaped-charge warhead designed to burn or punch its way through a vehicle or barrier. Though the impact causes a blast, it is limited compared to that of a High-Explosive projectile. AV attacks have an AP of -6 against vehicles, -2 against other targets.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
	<RocketMissile name="Fragmentation" type="Rocket">
		<Stats>Damage: 16P(f) AP: +5 Blast: -1m Radius Availability: 16F</Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>Used principally against people, the warhead discharges high-speed metal or plastic-metal fragments designed to tear into unprotected flesh. These rockets/missiles are very effective against unprotected individuals, but fairly ineffective against barriers, structures, and vehicles.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
	<RocketMissile name="High Explosive" type="Rocket">
		<Stats>Damage: 14P AP: -2 Blast: -2m Radius Availability: 20F</Stats>
		<Cost>750</Cost>
		<Desc>HE rockets/missiles are designed to do heavy damage to a large area. Their blast pattern is similar to that of a grenade, but much larger. They are not particularly effective against hardened targets, such as vehicles or protected military structures. HE weapons use the standard grenade rules for determining the blast and its effects.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
	<RocketMissile name="Anti-Vehicle" type="Missile">
		<Stats>Damage: 16P AP: -2/-6 Blast: -4m Radius Availability: 20F</Stats>
		<Cost>1500</Cost>
		<Desc>AV rockets/missiles contain a shaped-charge warhead designed to burn or punch its way through a vehicle or barrier. Though the impact causes a blast, it is limited compared to that of a High-Explosive projectile. AV attacks have an AP of -6 against vehicles, -2 against other targets.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
	<RocketMissile name="Fragmentation" type="Missile">
		<Stats>Damage: 16P(f) AP: +5 Blast: -1m Radius Availability: 16F</Stats>
		<Cost>1000</Cost>
		<Desc>Used principally against people, the warhead discharges high-speed metal or plastic-metal fragments designed to tear into unprotected flesh. These rockets/missiles are very effective against unprotected individuals, but fairly ineffective against barriers, structures, and vehicles.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
	<RocketMissile name="High Explosive" type="Missile">
		<Stats>Damage: 14P AP: -2 Blast: -2m Radius Availability: 20F</Stats>
		<Cost>1250</Cost>
		<Desc>HE rockets/missiles are designed to do heavy damage to a large area. Their blast pattern is similar to that of a grenade, but much larger. They are not particularly effective against hardened targets, such as vehicles or protected military structures. HE weapons use the standard grenade rules for determining the blast and its effects.</Desc>
	</RocketMissile>
<!-- End Rockets/Missiles -->
<!-- Start Explosives -->
	<Explosive name="Commercial">
		<Stats>Rating: 3 Availability: 8R</Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>This covers a range of explosive compounds, both solid and liquid, composed of a high explosive chemical and a stabilizer to reduce the sensitivity and increase the stability of the material.</Desc>
	</Explosive>
	<Explosive name="Foam">
		<Stats>Rating: 4-15 Availability: 12F</Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>This special plastic explosive compound has the consistency of shaving cream, is stored in an aerosol can, and can be sprayed onto a surface or into a crevice. Like regular plastic explosives, explosive foam is detonated by electric current.</Desc>
	</Explosive>
	<Explosive name="Plastic">
		<Stats>Rating: 4-15 Availability: 16F</Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>Highly stable, moldable, and adhesive, plastic explosives are ideal for certain jobs-like blowing a hole in a wall. They are usually color-tinted to indicate the level of current needed to detonate them, from the black of magnetic-field induction to the chalky white of 440-volt industrial explosives.</Desc>
	</Explosive>
	<Explosive name="Detonator Cap">
		<Stats>Rating: - Availability: 8R</Stats>
		<Cost>75</Cost>
		<Desc>Contains a detonator explosive or electrical fuse with which an explosion can be initiated. Incorporates a timer and wireless receiver for remote detonation.</Desc>
	</Explosive>
<!-- End Explosives -->
<!-- Start Clothing -->
	<Clothing name="Feedback Clothing">
		<Stats>B/I: 0/0 Availability: 8 </Stats>
		<Cost>600</Cost>
		<Desc>This clothing modification creates feedback and resistance in order to allow for a tactile augmented reality experience. This technology is still rare, as full immersion solutions are cheaper and also more effective.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Leather Jacket">
		<Stats>B/I: 2/2 Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>Whether a basic jacket or a knee-length duster, the leather jacket never goes out of style and offers a modicum of protection.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Actioneer Business Clothes">
		<Stats>B/I: 5/3 Availability: 8 </Stats>
		<Cost>1500</Cost>
		<Desc>These discreetly armored "power suits" are still tr&#232;s chic among Mr. Johnsons, fixers, and executives who are looking for a little high-class protection with their neo-Japanese style. Features a concealed holster (an additional -2 Concealability modifier) inside the jacket.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Armor Clothing">
		<Stats>B/I: 4/0 Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>The extra-resilient ballistic fiber in armor clothing offers basic protection while being indistinguishable from regular clothing.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Armor Jacket">
		<Stats>B/I: 8/6 Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>900</Cost>
		<Desc>The most popular armor solution on the streets comes in all styles imaginable. It offers good protection without catching too much attention, but don't think of wearing it to a dinner party.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Armor Vest">
		<Stats>B/I: 6/4 Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>600</Cost>
		<Desc>Modern flexible-wrap vests are designed to be worn under regular clothing without displaying any bulk.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Camoflauge Suit">
		<Stats>B/I: 8/6 Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>1200</Cost>
		<Desc>A full body suit with computer-designed environmental-pattern facsimiles. All have reversible day/night patterns. When worn in an appropriate environment, the suit inflicts a -2 Perception Test dice pool modifier to spot the wearer (if worn in an inappropriate environment, it incurs a +2 bonus instead). Also armored for additional protection.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
		<Clothing name="Chameleon Suit">
		<Stats>B/I: 6/4 Availability: 10R </Stats>
		<Cost>8000</Cost>
		<Desc>A full body suit made from ruthenium polymers supported by a sensor suite that scans the surroundings and replicates the images at the proper perspectives, providing the wearer with chameleon abilities. Apply a -4 dice pool modifier to Perception Tests to see the wearer. Also armored for additional protection.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Full Body Armor">
		<Stats>B/I: 10/8 Availability: 14R </Stats>
		<Cost>6000</Cost>
		<Desc>Worn by military and security personnel around the world, full body armor is often styled for intimidation as much as ease of movement. It features a padded undersuit, over which patches of liquid armor gel and extensive armor plates are attached. Though surprisingly lightweight, full body armor is certain to draw attention. In addition to an array of useful tactical gear and webbing, full body armor can be outfitted with environmental adaptation (for hot or cold environments) and/or a chemical seal to completely protect the wearer from toxic environments or attacks. Full body armor is electronically integrated with a wireless link, and can be enhanced with additional features such as vision enhancements, tracking/RFID signals, smartlink, and more.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Full Body Armor Helmet">
		<Stats>B/I: +2/+2 Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>1000</Cost>
		<Desc>The armor suit's helmet incorporates a wireless link and can be equipped with any of the vision enhancements noted on p. 333.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Full Body Armor Chemical Seal">
		<Stats>B/I: - Availability: +6 </Stats>
		<Cost>5000</Cost>
		<Desc>A chemical seal for Full Body Armor to completely protect the wearer from toxic environments or attacks.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Full Body Armor Environment Adaptation">
		<Stats>B/I: - Availability: +3 </Stats>
		<Cost>2000</Cost>
		<Desc>An environmental adaptation for Full Body Armor.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Lined Coat">
		<Stats>B/I: 6/4 Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>700</Cost>
		<Desc>Reminiscent of the long dusters worn in the days of the Wild West, lined coats offer good protection and also provide an additional -2 Concealability modifier to items hidden underneath.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Urban Explorer Jumpsuit">
		<Stats>B/I: 6/6 Availability: 8 </Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>Ideal for messengers, athletes, and anyone on-the-go, these colorful jumpsuits are well-ventilated for lots of action but surprisingly protective with light-weight densiplast and liquid reactive armor. Features a built-in music-player and biomonitor (p. 337).</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Urban Explorer Jumpsuit Helmet">
		<Stats>B/I: -/+2 Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>A matching helmet for the Urban Explorer Jumpsuit.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Helmet">
		<Stats>B/I: +1/+2 Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>Helmets come in a wide variety of shapes and sizes, but their common purpose is to protect the head from trauma. Helmets are often tricked out with accessories such as trode nets and visual aids.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Ballistic Shield">
		<Stats>B/I: +6/+4 Availability: 12R </Stats>
		<Cost>1500</Cost>
		<Desc>This large opaque shield is used for house raids and other SWAT activities. It features a clear plastic window and a built-in ladder frame along the inside so that it can be used to climb over small obstacles.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Riot Shield">
		<Stats>B/I: +2/+6 Availability: 6R </Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>The riot shield is made from clear plasteel and is mainly used for riot control.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<Clothing name="Taser Shield">
		<Stats>B/I: +2/+6 Availability: 10R </Stats>
		<Cost>750</Cost>
		<Desc>As an added crowd control measure, a taser shield can be used to shock anyone who comes into contact with it, inflicting Electricity damage (p. 163). The taser shield holds 20 charges; when attached to a power point, it reloads one charge per 10 seconds.</Desc>
	</Clothing>
	<ArmorModification name="Chemical Protection">
		<Stats>Availability: 8</Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>250</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>
		The application of water-resistant, nonporous, and impermeable materials helps protect the wearer against contact-vector chemical attacks (Toxin Protection, p. 254). For full body armor, this will also protect against inhalation-vector attacks.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
	<ArmorModification name="Fire Resistance">
		<Stats>Availability: 4</Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>100</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>Fire-retardant, heat-resistant, and nonflammable materials protect the wearer against Fire damage (p. 164), adding its full rating to the armor value.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
	<ArmorModification name="Insulation">
		<Stats>Availability: 4</Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>150</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>Thermal fibers, insulating layers, and heat-retentive materials protect the wearer against Cold damage (p. 163), adding its full rating to the armor value.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
	<ArmorModification name="Nonconductivity">
		<Stats>Availability: 6</Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>200</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>Electrical insulation and grounding materials protect the wearer against Electricity damage (p. 163), adding its full rating to the armor value.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
	<ArmorModification name="Shock Frills">
		<Stats>Reach: - Damage: 6S(e) Availability: 6R </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>1</CostMultiplier>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>These strips of "fur" are electrically charged when activated, standing on end and inflicting Electricity damage (p. 163) to anyone that comes into contact. this modification must be used with the nonconductivity modification (so that the wearer does not get shocked). Use unarmed Combat to attack with the frills. The frills hold 10 charges; when attached to a power point, they reload one charge per 10 seconds.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
	<ArmorModification name="Thermal Damping">
		<Stats>Availability: 10F</Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>500</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>Designed to reduce the wearer's thermal signature, inner layers capture and retain heat while outer layers maintain a surface temperature equal to the surrounding air. Thermal damping adds its rating as bonus to Infiltration Tests to avoid thermal sensors, thermographic vision, etc.
		</Desc>
	</ArmorModification>
<!-- End Clothing -->
<!-- Start Electronics -->
	<Commlink name="Meta Link">
		<Response>1</Response>
		<Signal>2</Signal>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="CMT Clip">
		<Response>1</Response>
		<Signal>3</Signal>
		<Cost>300</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Sony Emperor">
		<Response>2</Response>
		<Signal>3</Signal>
		<Cost>700</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Renraku Sensei">
		<Response>2</Response>
		<Signal>4</Signal>
		<Cost>10000</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Novatech Airwave">
		<Response>3</Response>
		<Signal>3</Signal>
		<Cost>1250</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Erika Elite">
		<Response>3</Response>
		<Signal>4</Signal>
		<Cost>2500</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Hermes Ikon">
		<Response>4</Response>
		<Signal>3</Signal>
		<Cost>3000</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Transys Avalon">
		<Response>4</Response>
		<Signal>4</Signal>
		<Cost>5000</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<Commlink name="Fairlight Caliban">
		<Response>4</Response>
		<Signal>5</Signal>
		<Cost>8000</Cost>
	</Commlink>
	<OperatingSystem name="Vector Xim">
		<Firewall>1</Firewall>
		<System>1</System>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<OperatingSystem name="Redcap Nix">
		<Firewall>1</Firewall>
		<System>2</System>
		<Cost>400</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<OperatingSystem name="Renraku Ichi">
		<Firewall>2</Firewall>
		<System>2</System>
		<Cost>600</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<OperatingSystem name="Mangadyne Deva">
		<Firewall>2</Firewall>
		<System>3</System>
		<Cost>800</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<OperatingSystem name="Iris Orb">
		<Firewall>3</Firewall>
		<System>3</System>
		<Cost>1000</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<OperatingSystem name="Novatech Navi">
		<Firewall>3</Firewall>
		<System>4</System>
		<Cost>1500</Cost>
	</OperatingSystem>
	<ProgramSuite name="Basic User">
		<Programs>
			<MatrixProgram name="Analyze">
				<Rating>2</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Browse">
				<Rating>2</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Command">
				<Rating>1</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Edit">
				<Rating>2</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
		</Programs>
		<Cost>300</Cost>
	</ProgramSuite>
	<ProgramSuite name="Basic+">
		<Programs>
			<MatrixProgram name="Analyze">
				<Rating>3</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Browse">
				<Rating>3</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Command">
				<Rating>1</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Edit">
				<Rating>3</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
		</Programs>
		<Cost>400</Cost>
	</ProgramSuite>
	<ProgramSuite name="Pro User">
		<Programs>
			<MatrixProgram name="Analyze">
				<Rating>4</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Browse">
				<Rating>4</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Command">
				<Rating>2</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Edit">
				<Rating>4</Rating>
			</MatrixProgram>
		</Programs>
		<Cost>600</Cost>
	</ProgramSuite>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="AR Gloves">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>250</Cost>
		<Desc>Available in all sizes and shapes, these gloves allow the user to manually interact with the Matrix, by manipulating virtual arrows, accessing a virtual keyboard or display, or remotely controlling a device. They are also equipped with force feedback, allowing for a limited tactile augmented reality experience. These gloves are also able to provide basic information regarding touched or held items, such as weight, temperature, and hardness.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Biometric Reader">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>For controlled access to online accounts or certain devices, the proper biometric scan must be provided (Biometrics, p. 265). A different reader is required for each type of biometric data.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Nanopaste Trodes">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 2 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>This highly sensitive, high-tech nanite paste can be used to "paint" an electrode net around the head. Popular with the club-going set, nanopaste is often artistically applied in a variety of colors and designs.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Printer">
		<DeviceRating>1</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>5</Cost>
		<Desc>Disposable full-color printers come attached to the paper container.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Satellite Link">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>This allows the user to uplink to communication satellites in low-Earth orbit, connecting to the Matrix from places where no local wireless networks exist. This link has a Signal rating of 8. Includes a portable satellite dish.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Sim Module">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>The sim module is an interface device that controls the simsense experience. It translates computer signals (simsense data) into neural signals, allowing the user to directly experience simsense programs, augmented and virtual reality (Virtual Reality, p. 220). A sim module must be accessed via trodes or a direct neural interface (datajack, implanted commlink, etc.). Standard (legal) sim modules only interpret cold sim (p. 226). It is possible to modify a sim module to allow the user to experience hot sim (p. 226) and BTLs (p. 259) with a Hardware + Logic (10, 1 hour) Extended Test, but this also makes the user more vulnerable to Black IC programs. As a precaution against hijacking, modified modules have a physical switch to change between cold and hot sim. As a safety precaution, sim mods override your motor functions while you are fully immersed in VR/simsense, so that you don't blindly thrash around in the real world and potentially injure yourself or break things. This means that your physical body is limp while you're online, as if you were sleeping. This reticular activation system (RAS) override can also be disabled with a Hardware + Logic (5, 1 hour) Extended Test, at the user's own risk.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Modified Sim Module for BTL/Hot Sim">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 4F </Stats>
		<Cost>250</Cost>
		<Desc>The sim module is an interface device that controls the simsense experience. It translates computer signals (simsense data) into neural signals, allowing the user to directly experience simsense programs, augmented and virtual reality (Virtual Reality, p. 220). A sim module must be accessed via trodes or a direct neural interface (datajack, implanted commlink, etc.). Standard (legal) sim modules only interpret cold sim (p. 226). It is possible to modify a sim module to allow the user to experience hot sim (p. 226) and BTLs (p. 259) with a Hardware + Logic (10, 1 hour) Extended Test, but this also makes the user more vulnerable to Black IC programs. As a precaution against hijacking, modified modules have a physical switch to change between cold and hot sim. As a safety precaution, sim mods override your motor functions while you are fully immersed in VR/simsense, so that you don't blindly thrash around in the real world and potentially injure yourself or break things. This means that your physical body is limp while you're online, as if you were sleeping. This reticular activation system (RAS) override can also be disabled with a Hardware + Logic (5, 1 hour) Extended Test, at the user's own risk.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Simrig">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 12 </Stats>
		<Cost>1000</Cost>
		<Desc>An advanced version of the trode net, the simrig records simsense experience data (both physical and emotive) from the wearer. Simrigs incorporate a sim module.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Skinlink">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 6 </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>
		With skinlink, a device is adapted to send and receive data transmitted through the electrical field on the surface of metahuman skin. Though limited to touch, skinlink communication has the advantage of being protected from signal interception or jamming.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Subvocal Microphone">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 6 </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>Attached with adhesive to the center of the throat, this hard-to-spot microphone allows the user to communicate via subvocalized speech. A -4 dice pool modifier is applied to audio Perception Tests to overhear what she is saying.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Trodes">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>50</Cost>
		<Desc>This net/headband of electrodes and ultrasound emitters enables the wearer to experience simsense and is used with a sim module. Trodes are often concealed under headbands, hats, or wigs.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Electronic Paper">
		<DeviceRating>1</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>20</Cost>
		<Desc>This electronic sheet is roughly the size of a piece of paper and can be folded to fit into a pocket. It digitally displays any input data and can act as a customizable touchscreen controller.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Holo Projector">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>200</Cost>
		<Desc>This device projects a trideo hologram into any open space within 5 meters. Though holos can be quite realistic, a Perception + Intuition (2) Test is usually sufficient to distinguish a hologram from a real object or person.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Standard RFID Tags">
		<DeviceRating>1</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: - </Stats>
		<Cost>1</Cost>
		<Desc>RFID (Radio Frequency Identification) tags form an integral part of every product that leaves the production line. Ranging in size from microscopic to the size of a price tag, tags have a stick-to-anything adhesive backing and can sometimes be difficult to spot. Tags are programmed to transmit small amounts of data: serial numbers, product specs, and pricing (for distribution and retail); arrows and advertisements (for geo-tagging locations and objects, leaving a virtual AR message for anyone who comes by); ID (for employee tracking and access control); owner contact information (in case an item is stolen); vehicle registration; etc. Tags can be used as tracking devices, periodically transmitting to local scanners or to the wireless Matrix (along with the local access point's GPS data), though their limited range makes them useless in dead zones. RFID Tag data is often fixed, but in some cases is reprogrammable. Tags are readable by anyone with a commlink. They have a Signal rating of 1. The physical location of a tag can be found with a radio signal scanner (p. 334). Tag data can be erased with a tag eraser (p. 330) or programmed with an Edit program (which is what runners do to create fake tags). Fixed tag data can only be altered if the tag is physically accessed, requiring a Hardware + Logic (5, 1 minute) Extended Test. Data on a tag may be encrypted.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Security Tags">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>100</Cost>
		<Desc>Security-conscious megacorps often implant security tags in their salarymen and valued citizens (usually in the hand or arm). These tags are used to monitor employees' workplace activities, grant clearance to authorized devices and areas (and alert security when detected in unauthorized areas), and provide a means of tracking in case of abduction. These same tags are also used on criminals, both in the joint and when released on parole/monitoring conditions. Parents and schools also use them to track students. Security tags are hardened so that they cannot be erased with a tag eraser. Tags can be easily implanted under the skin at no Essence Cost. Removing them requires a First Aid + Logic (8, 1 minute) Extended Test. Many security systems will trigger an alert if a security tag in their bounds is deactivated.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Sensor Tags">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 4 </Stats>
		<Cost>500</Cost>
		<Desc>These tags are equipped with single rating 1 sensor (Visual Sensors &amp; Imaging Devices, p. 332; Audio Sensors, p. 333; and Sensors, p. 333) and are programmed to monitor a certain object/ person/environment and respond to certain conditions. Sensor tags are used for diagnostic purposes in various devices, vehicle components, and cyberware, as well as to monitor temperature in food shipments, and many similar purposes. Sensor purchased separately.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Stealth Tags">
		<DeviceRating>3</DeviceRating>
		<Stats>Availability: 6 </Stats>
		<Cost>5</Cost>
		<Desc>Stealth tags are encoded to remain silent and only respond to transmissions with the proper passcodes. They cannot be located with a commlink or bug scanner (unless the codes are known). They typically use special frequencies and other tricks to avoid detection. These tags are also disguised so as not to look like RFID tags (an additional -2 Concealability). Stealth tags are often used as a backup for security tags, and may be implanted in the same way.
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<CommAccessory name="Headjammer">
		<Stats>Availability: 6R </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>250</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>The headjammer is used by security personnel to prevent the use of headware commlinks and communication systems. When the headjammer is attached to a person's head and activated, it works in the same way as a jammer, but its effects are limited to that person's head.
		</Desc>
	</CommAccessory>
	<CommAccessory name="Jammer, Area">
		<Stats>Availability: (Rating x 3)F </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>500</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>This device floods the airwaves with electromagnetic jamming signals to block out wireless and radio communication. The jammer automatically jams any device with a Signal rating lower than its Device rating. The area jammer affects a spherical area-its rating is reduced by 1 for every 5 meters from the center (similar to the blast rules for grenades). 
		</Desc>
	</CommAccessory>
	<CommAccessory name="Jammer, Directional">
		<Stats>Availability: (Rating x 2)F </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>500</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>This device floods the airwaves with electromagnetic jamming signals to block out wireless and radio communication. The jammer automatically jams any device with a Signal rating lower than its Device rating. The directional jammer affects a conical area with a 30-degree spread-its rating is reduced by 1 for every 20 meters from the center. Walls and other obstacles may prevent the jamming signal from spreading or reduce its effect (gamemaster's discretion).
		</Desc>
	</CommAccessory>
	<CommAccessory name="Micro-Transceiver">
		<Stats>Availability: Rating x 2 </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>200</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>This classic short-range communication device is perfect for discreet operations. The micro-transceiver consists of an earbud and adhesive subvocal microphone (p. 328). The transceiver's Signal rating is equal to its Device rating.
		</Desc>
	</CommAccessory>
	<ElectronicAccessory name="Tag Eraser">
		<Stats>Availability: 6F </Stats>
		<Cost>150</Cost>
		<Desc>This handheld device creates a strong electromagnetic field that burns out RFID tags. The eraser must be brought within 1 centimeter of the target, but will automatically burn any non-hardened tag out, no test required. The eraser's electromagnetic field is also capable of erasing/scrambling other non-optical electronic circuit systems at the gamemaster's discretion. The eraser cannot burn out security RFID tags (p. 329).
		</Desc>
	</ElectronicAccessory>
	<CommAccessory name="White Noise Generator">
		<Stats>Availability: Rating + 1 </Stats>
		<CostMultiplier>50</CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>This device creates a field of random noise, masking the sounds within its area. All Perception Tests to overhear a conversation within 10 meters of a white noise generator receive a negative dice pool modifier equal to the generator's rating. If more than one generator is in use, only count the highest rating.
		</Desc>
	</CommAccessory>
	
<!-- End Electronics -->
	<MatrixProgramCategory name="Common Use">
		<Stats>Availability>: - </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>50</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>100</Rating6CostMultiplier>
		<Programs>
			<MatrixProgram name="Analyze (Computer)">
				<Desc>Analyze programs gather data about icons and nodes in the Matrix by issuing queries, analyzing system resources, performing registry lookups, and so on. Use Analyze for Matrix Perception (p. 228). An Analyze program running in a node also helps detect hacking attempts (p. 235).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Browse (Data Search)">
				<Desc>Browse programs are specialized search routines that help track down information on a particular node or in the Matrix at large. Use Browse programs for Data Search actions (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Command (Varies)">
				<Desc>Command programs give the user a modular and customizable control interface for various devices. This allows the user to control a device through the Matrix (p. 245), whether it be a surveillance camera, a drone, or any other Matrix-capable device.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Edit (Computer)">
				<Desc>Edit is a combination word processor, graphic design tool, and video/animation editor. You can use it to create and alter files of any media type: text, graphics, video, trideo, simsense, etc. Edit sees common usage in the corporate world, but hackers use it for their own subversive ends. Use Edit with the Edit action (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Encrypt (Electronic Warfare)">
				<Desc>Encrypt programs utilize various cryptographic schemes and ciphers to secure files, nodes, and communications. Encrypted items can be decrypted with the proper passcode, otherwise they are gibberish. Use Encrypt programs for the Encrypt action (p. 229).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Reality Filter (Response)">
				<Desc>A Reality Filter program translates a node's VR sculpting into a metaphor of your choice by attempting to interpret the node's algorithms. When you first run this program or enter a node while it is running, make an Opposed Test between your Reality Filter + Response and the node's System + Response. If the filter wins, your preprogrammed paradigm overrides the node's signals and you receive a +1 Response bonus while in that node. If the node wins, or a tie results, its metaphor overwhelms the filter enough that you suffer -1 Response while in the node.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Scan (Electronic Warfare)">
				<Desc>Scan programs allow you to locate wireless networks. Every wireless device has a built-in Scan program at rating 1, but users who want better access control may upgrade to a superior utility. Scan is used for the Detect Hidden Node action (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
		</Programs>
		<Desc>Common use programs are widespread and legal throughout the Matrix.
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
	<MatrixProgramCategory name="Hacking">
		<Stats>Availability>: (Rating x 2)R </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>500</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>1000</Rating6CostMultiplier>
				<Programs>
			<MatrixProgram name="Armor (None)">
				<Desc>Armor programs are software redundancy and automatic backup systems that protect icons from attacks that cause Matrix damage (p. 237).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Attack (Cybercombat/Hacking)">
				<Desc>Attack programs are hostile code carriers that attempt to kill processes, introduce random input, create program faults, and otherwise try to crash an icon or program. They are used in cybercombat (p. 236).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Biofeedback Filter (None)">
				<Desc>Biofeedback filters are software routines that monitor simsense signals and filter harmful feedback. Hackers specifically use biofeedback filters as a defense against Black Hammer and Blackout programs in cybercombat (p. 236) and against dumpshock (p. 237). Technomancers have an inherent Biofeedback Filter complex form equal to their Charisma, and so cannot take this as a complex form.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Black Hammer (Cybercombat)">
				<Desc>Black Hammer is a black IC program that samples the command transactions between the target and his commlink and injects dangerous biofeedback responses into the target's simsense interface. These aggravated signals may overload the target's neural connections and in turn render him unconscious or cause death from stroke, heart failure, respiratory paralysis, aneurysm, or neurotransmitter autotoxicity-and those are just a few of the possible effects. It is used with the Matrix Attack action (p. 231). Black Hammer is intended as a weapon against hackers in full VR using hot sim, causing Physical damage rather than Matrix damage in cybercombat (p. 237). Against cold sim VR users, it only inflicts Stun damage. It has no effect on programs, agents, IC, sprites, or AR users.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Blackout (Cybercombat)">
				<Desc>Blackout is black IC program that is a non-lethal version of Black Hammer. It causes Stun damage to both hot sim and cold sim VR users. Like Black Hammer, it is used with the Matrix Attack action (p. 231) and has no effect on programs, agents, IC, sprites, or AR users. Damage from Blackout does not overflow into the Physical Condition Monitor.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Data Bomb (None))">
				<Desc>Data Bomb programs create a specialized form of reactive executable in a file or node, called a data bomb (note the difference in capitalization: Data Bomb is the program, whereas a data bomb is the executable set by the program). A data bomb is attached to a specific file or node and set to activate if someone accesses the file or node without authorization. When triggered, a data bomb "explodes" and attempts to crash the icon that accessed the file or node. Data bombs may also be instructed to erase the file or crash the node, if the owner chooses. Data bombs are set with the Set Data Bomb action (p. 231). Only one data bomb may be attached to a particular file or device. You can detect a data bomb with a successful Matrix Perception Test. You can defuse a data bomb simply by entering the correct passcode. Without the passcode, you can only disable a detected data bomb with a successful Disarm Data Bomb action (p. 231). When it "detonates," a data bomb inflicts a number of boxes of Matrix damage equal to (rating x 1D6), then the data bomb is deleted.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Decrypt (Electronic Warfare)">
				<Desc>Decrypt programs are designed to conduct a number of cipher-busting attacks-from pattern analysis to brute-force dictionary assaults to sophisticated mathematical tricks-to break into an encrypted system or service. Use Decrypt programs for Initiate Cryptanalysis actions (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Defuse (Hacking)">
				<Desc>The sole purpose of the Defuse program is to deactivate data bombs that are protecting files or devices. It is used with the Disarm Data Bomb action (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="ECCM (None)">
				<Desc>Electronic counter-countermeasures (ECCM) filter out jamming signals that attempt to disrupt a wireless connection. An ECCM program adds its rating to the Signal rating of the device on which it is running when defending against jamming (see p. 246).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Exploit (Hacking)">
				<Desc>Exploit programs are constantly evolving hacker tools specifically designed to take advantage of security flaws and weaknesses so that a hacker can gain unauthorized access to a node or program. Exploit programs are used with the Hack on the Fly action (p. 230), Probing the Target for weaknesses (p. 236), and Crashing Nodes and Programs (p. 230).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Medic (Computer)">
				<Desc>Use Medic to repair Matrix damage inflicted on icons. Though legitimate users sometimes use Medic to fix corrupted files, misbehaving programs, and other errors, hackers use Medic to keep functioning after a bout of cybercombat. Some IC programs carry Medic programs to repair themselves. Use Medic for the Repair Icon action (p. 231). While this program cannot help technomancers, they may use the Medic complex form to repair other icons, such as personas, agents, or sprites.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Sniffer (Electronic Warfare/Hacking)">
				<Desc>Sniffer programs gather data traffic and wireless signals and capture the information. Sniffer programs are the ultimate Matrix spying utility, used for the Intercept Traffic (p. 230) and Capture Wireless Signals (p. 229) actions.
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Spoof (Hacking)">
				<Desc>You can use Spoof programs to generate false access IDs and forge misleading data packets with the intent of confusing Track programs. Use Spoof for the Redirect Trace action (p. 231) or the Spoof Command action (p. 232).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Stealth (Hacking)">
				<Desc>Stealth is a clever hacker program that attempts to hide the hacker from other system processes. While it cannot make an icon completely undetectable, it makes the hacker seem innocuous by obfuscating his activities, erasing system tracks, and mimicking authorized traffic. While it is not used for any action, Stealth hides the hacker from detection by the Firewall as he breaks into a system (p. 227), as well as from  Matrix Perception tests (p. 228) and Trace User attempts (p. 232).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
			<MatrixProgram name="Track (Computer)">
				<Desc>Track programs systematically analyze a user's connection and follow the datatrail back to the originating node. Track is commonly used as an intrusion countermeasure with the intent of identifying/locating a hacker or launching a counterattack, but it is also used to keep tabs on automated taxis and emergency service calls. Track is used for the Trace User action (p. 232).
				</Desc>
			</MatrixProgram>
		</Programs>
		<Desc>The following programs are generally only used by hackers and security specialists. In most jurisdictions, these programs are illegal without proper licensing. Hackers use these programs to exploit security flaws and attack icons. IC programs use them against intruders (p. 237).
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
	<MatrixProgramCategory name="Agents/IC/Pilot">
		<Stats>Availability>: Rating x 3 </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>1000</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>2500</Rating6CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
	<MatrixProgramCategory name="System">
		<Stats>Availability>: - </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>200</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>500</Rating6CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
	<MatrixProgramCategory name="Firewall">
		<Stats>Availability>: - </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>200</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>500</Rating6CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
		<MatrixProgramCategory name="Autosofts (Rating 1-4)">
		<Stats>Availability>: Rating x 2 </Stats>
		<Rating3CostMultiplier>500</Rating3CostMultiplier>
		<Rating6CostMultiplier>1000</Rating6CostMultiplier>
		<Desc>
		</Desc>
	</MatrixProgramCategory>
</Rulebook>